一個月前
貝艾爾市
“我們在船上,賤人!” 漢普頓斯09年三角洲基金休閒館
金錢
早安,西西裡奧!
Buenos dias, Cecelio!
先生,你們的廣告上說: “不良信貸,沒問題”
Sir, I'm just saying, your ad says, "Bad credit, no problem."
你能給我說說什麼 叫“沒問題”嗎?
So can you define "no problem"?
我沒拿到這筆貸款 就是個問題
Because me not getting this loan is a problem.
對不起,所以我才叫你...
I'm sorry. That's why I'm asking you to...
- 對不起,爸爸 - 沒關係,就是有點噁心
- Sorry, Daddy. - That's okay, but that's just nasty.
不,不是說你,先生
No, no, no. Not you, sir.
出售中 好學區! 好,聽我說:如果萬事具備只欠三萬美金 我該如何呢?
Listen to this. What if I have everything I need except the $30,000?
保持冷靜?先生,先生,能否...?
Keep calm? Sir. Sir. Can you...?
女士,好的,我聽不出來
Ma'am. Okay. I couldn't tell.
你難道不該是掠奪放款人嗎? 快來吞噬我吧!
Aren't you supposed to be a predatory lender? Then prey on me!
好嗎?你是威猛的獅子 我是羸弱的小羚羊
Okay? You're a lion, I'm a gazelle.
好,我告訴你 我這就把女兒叫過來聽電話...
Okay, fine. Fine. Do you know what? I'm putting my daughter on the phone.
你來跟她解釋一下她為何要去 上這麼一所遍布犯罪少年的...
Explain to her why she has to go to school in a gangbanger school district...
殺害孩子的學校,殺害!
where they're murdering kids. Murdering!
來吧,你告訴她
Here, you tell her.
嘿,寶貝,按我教你的做
Hey, baby, do what I showed you.
- 你為什麼要讓我去找死? - 不
- Why do you want me to get murdered? - No.
殺害,你為什麼要讓我去找死?
IN WHINY VOICE "Murdered. Why do you want me to get murdered?"
他們掛了
They hung up.
寶貝,因為你沒按照我教你的來
IN NORMAL VOICE Because you're not doing what I told you to.
- 你有病 - 我沒病,這叫孤注一擲
- You are sick. - I'm not sick. It's called desperate.
寶貝,我們只要省吃儉用就好
Baby, all we have to do is keep saving.
我需要一些關懷 能抱我一下嗎?
I just need some love. Can you just hug me?
親我一下好嗎?
Just kiss me?
- 好點嗎? - 氣氛好奇怪
- RITA: Any better? - Awkward.
過來,拿上你的果汁和書包
Come on. Get your juice, and your book bag.
我告訴過你要擊中靶心
I told you to hit the bull's-eye.
哭一下有多難,瑪凱拉?
How hard is it to cry, Makayla?
“殺害,殺害”
IN WHINY VOICE "Murder. Murder."
中南部下城
- 當心 - 閃開,老頭兒
- DARNELL: Watch out. - BOY: Move, old man.
那是大麻嗎?
Is that weed?
嘿,要注意安全,聽到沒?
Hey, I want you to be safe, okay?
聽我說,聽我說 你不會永遠都待在這所學校的
Listen to me. Listen to me. You're not gonna be at this school forever.
爸爸已經在想辦法了,我愛你
Daddy's working on it. I love you.
- 我也愛你 - 好了
- I love you too. - DARNELL: All right.
- 別擔心 - 不擔心有點難,你是我女兒啊
- MAKAYLA: Don't worry. - Kind of hard not to worry. You're my daughter.
- 快走吧,寶貝 - 嘿,當心!
- Come on, dear. - Hey, watch it!
只是時間問題
Matter of time. Matter of time.
- 我要踢了,詹姆斯! - 好
- I kick, James! - Yeah.
閃開!
Move!
旋風腿!
JAOA SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
- 嘿,寶貝! - 親愛的,看看這個
- Hey, babe! - Watch this, honey.
看這個
Watch this.
看那踢腿!
Whoo! Look at that kick!
乾得漂亮,詹姆斯!
Good job, James!
漂亮,我們今天都很刻苦
Good job, guys. We're all working hard today. Mm.
我高大威猛的未婚夫 你在那兒看起來相當棒
ALISSA: You looked good out there, my big strong fiancé.
喬安說我應該專注在 把自己的力量帶到這個世界
Jaoa says I need to focus on bringing my power into the world.
媽的!
Fuck!
也許我能幫上忙
Maybe I can help.
你...
You...
真是個大好人,詹姆斯·金
are a great man, James King.
在新房子裡找上我
Do me on the new house.
ALISSA MOANING
它變大了嗎?
Did it get bigger?
是的,寶貝
Yeah, it did, baby.
它是陰莖之王,是你的權杖
It's the dick of a king. It's your scepter.
- 不是 - 是
- No. - Yeah.
不是,我是指房子
No, I mean the house.
詹姆斯,國王需要他的城堡
The king needs his castle, James.
一萬平方英尺
Ten thousand square feet.
七個臥室
Seven bedrooms.
兩個廚房
Two kitchens.
無限大的泳池
WHISPERS Infinity pool.
那是客房中的客房?
Is that a guesthouse for the guesthouse?
以防客人又帶客人來
IN NORMAL VOICE Well, in case our guests have guests.
你的朋友那麼多,寶貝
And you have so many friends, baby.
是不是,香餑餑先生?
Don't you, Mr. Popular?
太給力了
So powerful.
你不覺得這房子太大了嗎?
So you don't think it's too much house, do you?
詹姆斯,你是認真的?
James, seriously?
你真要在這房子裡居家過日子嗎?
I mean, you wanna raise a family in this house?
- 是的 - 在這...
- Well, yes. - In this...
房子裡?
house?
不!
No!
不,這房子就是個鬼地方!
No, this house is a shithole!
瞧...
Look...
有人歡喜有人愁,詹姆斯
there's winners and there's losers, James.
正是這推動著國家
It's what drives this country.
對嗎?人們盯著你的所有...
All right? People look at what you have...
想據為己有
and they want it.
他們想要你的豪宅
They want your huge house.
他們想要...
And they want...
你那熱辣的,熱辣的...
your hot, hot...
- 妻子 - 那麼火辣
- wife. - So hot.
- 誰是王? - 我是
- Who's the king? - I am.
你是王? 你今天能掙多少錢?
Are you the king? How much money you gonna make today?
- 足夠噎死一個嬰孩 - 沒錯
- Enough to choke a baby. - That's right.
- 是啊,你是贏家嗎? - 沒錯,我是
- Yeah, are you a winner? - Yes, I'm a winner.
- 這是誰的奶子? - 我的
- Whose tits are these? - They're my tits.
這些是王的乳頭!
These are the king's tits!
- 王的乳頭 - 沒錯
- The king's titties. - That's right.
- 這是王的弟弟嗎? - 尺寸中等偏上呢
- Is it a king's dick? - It's slightly above average.
是嗎?你得表明立場,詹姆斯
Yeah? You gotta stake your claim, James.
沒錯!你要表明立場!
Yes! You gotta stake it!
表明我的立場
Stake my claim.
噢,來啊,寶貝 像億萬富翁一樣挺我吧!
ALISSA: Oh, come on, baby. Do me like a billionaire!
主演:威爾·法瑞爾 你,就是你,戴上那頂帽子
You. You, right there, with the hat.
凱文·哈特
《獄前教育》
提普·哈里斯
愛麗森·布裡
*我不屑一顧
MOUTHING I don't care
威爾索普基金管理
賺美元
偶是神
嘿,老闆,你收到我的短信了嗎?
Hey, boss man, did you get that text?
我昨天給你發了一個短信
I sent you a text yesterday.
大驚喜!
Surprise!
老闆在這兒呢
The boss is here.
或許我們該表現得 像有工作要做
Maybe it's time that we act like we got work to do.
我們有四十部汽車 在這裡有八小時!
We got 40 cars and we got eight hours of the air down here!
詹姆斯·金,威爾索普基金管理
James King, Wealthrop Funds.
從我委託人賬戶轉一億過去
Transfer 100 million from my client accounts.
我想買布萊德威化學的盤 直到七點五
I'd like to put a buy order on Bradway Chemical, up to 7.50.
我對精煤把握不錯
I've got a good feeling about clean coal.
邁克,清潔一下車頂
Clean the roofs, Mike.
好萊塢豪華泡泡洗車中心 你不覺得大家能看到那些嗎? 我雇你是要做一件事
You don't think people can see those? I hired you to do one thing.
就是因為你高高噠
That's be tall.
不錯,好樣的
All right, great job.
嘿,詹姆斯,很精彩啊
Hey there, Jamesy, that was quite a ride, man.
股市收盤 就像二零一二年第三季度一樣
That was like third quarter 2012.
- 看你工作真是享受啊,先生 - 謝謝你,利奧
- It's a real pleasure to watch you work, sir. - Thanks, Leo.
嗯,怎麼樣,你知道我的名字!
Yeah. How about that, you knew my name!
我很喜歡
I love it.
導演:伊坦·柯亨 我撤回一些天然氣,繼續跟進煤礦
So I shorted gas and went long on coal.
收益不容樂觀,不過...
It wasn't quite the return I was hoping for, but...
詹姆斯
James.
你今天為我的公司 賺了兩千八百萬美元
You made my company $28 million today.
我想提早送你一份 結婚禮物來慶祝一下...
Now, to celebrate, I would like to give you an early wedding present...
合作夥伴
- partner. - Ah.
先生,謝謝你
Sir, thank you.
蓋爾,我們單獨聊一下
Gayle, a minute.
詹姆斯,就在此刻 你跨過那道門檻...
James, this is the moment when you cross that threshold...
加入了美國的社會名流
and join America's most elite.
你渴望的一切,想得到的一切都是你的了
Anything you desire, anything you want is yours.
我準備好了
I'm ready for it.
我在佛得角買了一塊島
You know, I bought an island in Cape Verde.
一整塊島
An entire island.
你也可以的
You can too.
我很願意,我們可以做島鄰
I would love to. We could be island neighbors.
你可以游過來 借一杯黃金
You could swim over and borrow a cup of gold.
好
Yeah.
想想這一切都始於此
You know, and to think it all started with this.
我還留著那台電腦呢
I still have that computer.
它提醒著我卑微的出身
It reminds me of my humble beginnings.
我如何一手創辦了這個公司
How I built this company with my own two hands.
當時只有我,那台電腦...
Just me, that computer...
以及從我爸爸那裡 貸來的八百萬美元
and an $8 million loan from my father.
你確實完全靠自己
You really did it all on your own.
非常勵志,先生
Very inspiring, sir.
現在聽著,不許再說 “先生”這類廢話
Now, listen, I want you to drop this "sir" nonsense.
看在老天的份上,你要娶我的女兒
You are marrying my daughter, for Pete's sake.
我希望你叫我“爸爸”
I want you to call me "Dad."
真的嗎?爸爸?
Really? Dad?
感覺很不錯
That feels very good.
我的親生爸爸從沒有時間陪我
My real father never had time for me.
他送我去倫敦的寄宿學校跟默多克和本·拉登 兩個家族呆在一起
He shipped me off to boarding school in London with the Murdochs and the bin Ladens.
當然了,那是以前...
Of course, that was before...
我們知道他們踢假球 但不知道...
I mean, we knew they cheated in soccer, but, had no idea...
其實...
you know...
可如果我能選擇一個爸爸...
But if I could choose a dad...
嘿,我跟你說 你們現在是一家人,孩子
Hey, you know something, you're family now, kid.
好啦
Okay, then.
好了
Oh, boy.
混賬東西
Motherfucker.
金先生
- Mr. King. - Aah! Aah!
盡情拿你想要的東西吧!
Take whatever you want!
- 請! - 噢,風帽讓你誤會了
- Please! - It's the hood.
- 嘿!是達內爾 - 救命!
- Hey! It's Darnell. - Help!
- 救命! - 住手,金先生,不要!
- Help! Help! - Stop! Mr. King. No!
- 噢,親愛的上帝,救命啊! - 住手!你太荒唐了!
- Oh, dear Lord. Someone help me! - Stop it! You're being ridiculous!
停!看看我
Stop! Look at me.
是我啊
It's me.
你的鑰匙給你!
I got your keys!
沒錯!我看見你了
Yes! I see you.
抱歉,我不是有意要嚇你
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
給你
- Here you go. - Oh.
- 對不起 - 謝謝
- I'm sorry. - Thank you.
如你所知,如果你是白人 我也會做同樣的事情
And, uh, just so you know, I would have done the same thing if you were white.
幸好知道了
That's good to know.
嘿,金先生
Hey, Mr. King.
你既然在這兒了,我就想... 我想跟你說上一會兒話
While I got you out here, I just wanna... I just wanna talk to you for a second.
到目前為止,我為你 洗車已達兩年之久...
I've been washing your car for two years now...
我能看出來你是那類 喜歡最上等東西的人
and I can tell you're the type of man who likes the best of everything.
因此,作為好萊塢豪華泡泡的 老闆和首席執行官...
So as owner and CEO of Hollywood Luxury Bubbles...
我想給您一張 價值三萬美金的...
I wanted to offer you an exclusive platinum lifetime wash card...
獨家白金終身洗車卡
for $30,000.
在你開口之前...
Now, before you say anything...
先想想這筆投資會給你 節省的金錢數額
think about the type of money that you'll save with this investment.
實際上,金錢的時間價值是...
Well, actually the time value of money is such that...
如果我把同等金額的錢財 投放到我自己的基金...
if I were to put that same amount in my own fund...
長達二十三年之久 我已經至少收穫了三百萬
in 23 years' time, I'd have in excess of $3 million.
哇,沒錯
Wow. Yeah.
根據那樣的回報率,我可以每次 在車髒了的時候再買一部新車
With that rate of return, I could buy a new car every time it gets dirty.
- 這不是很令人深刻嗎? - 太讓人吃驚了,金先生
- Isn't that impressive? - Amazing, Mr. King.
你知道的,我走到今天的位置...
That's the magic of compounded interest.
不是別人救濟的
You see, I didn't get to where I am today by asking for handouts.
而是通過努力工作
But by hard work.
今天,那樣的努力工作 終於得到了回報...
And today, that hard work paid off...
而我剛剛被提升為公司的合夥人
as I was just named partner in my firm.
金先生,那...
Mr. King, that is...
- 太了不起了 - 非常感謝
- Hey. That is amazing. - Thank you so much.
- 那... - 謝謝
- That is... - Thank you.
太令人吃驚了,金先生,聽我說
That's amazing. Mr. King, listen to me.
我是你所遇到過的最勤奮的工人之一了
I'm one of the hardest workers you'll ever meet.
所以我每天都在這裡洗車
I mean, that's why I'm down here power-washing cars every day.
我覺得面對面交談
I just felt with this face-to-face that you would...
可以讓你幫一個老闆同行和工作創造者
That you would wanna help a fellow business owner and job creator.
我是在幫你啊,所以我說不了
I am helping you. By saying no.
- 金先生,這... - 那樣,你就能自力更生了
- Mr. King, that's... - That way, you can make it on your own.
好了,金先生,已經有很多人這樣幫我了
Okay. Mr. King, I have a lot of people helping me that way already. And... And...
太好了,那你應該有成功大計了
Great. Then you have a plan for success.
之前怎麼不說?
Why didn't you tell me that?
你看,每個人無論出身 富裕還是貧困...
You see, everyone, whether we're born rich or poor...
無論是白人...
or white...
還是其他人種...
or miscellaneous...
我們會成為什麼樣的人...
who we become...
取決於我們自己的選擇,就這麼簡單
is based on our own decisions. It's simple as that.
你知道還有誰是從車庫起家的嗎?
You know who else started in a garage?
惠普- 帕卡德 所以你在的公司很好
Hewlett-Packard. So you're in good company.
- 關於這一點... - 不,先生...
- And on that note... - No, Mister...
- 你不必給我那麼多,金先生 - 等等,等等
- You don't have to give me that much, Mr. King. - Hold on, hold on.
- 金先生,你不必給我那麼多的 - 等等,有了
- You don't have to give me that much. - Hold on. There we go.
你真的不必...
You really don't need...
給你
There you go.
這只是開始
There's a start.
金先生,拜託,我感覺你還沒給我...
Mr. King, please. I feel like you just haven't given me...
成功是一種心態!
Success is a mindset!
大家好!
Hi, everyone!
你好
ALL: Hi.
非常感謝各位賞光 來慶祝我們的訂婚
Thank you so much for celebrating our engagement with us.
不好意思
Excuse me.
不好意思,大家請安靜
Excuse me. Everyone, just "shh."
噓,你得安靜,參議員
Shh! You need to "shh." Senator.
黃領帶
Yellow tie.
我看到你了
I see you.
謝謝
Thank you.
詹姆斯,我愛你...
James, I love you...
我真想馬上嫁給你
and I can't wait to be married to you.
因為你顛覆了我的世界...
And because you rock my world...
我要送這個給你!
I got you this!
真美
This is beautiful.
不過不如你美,艾麗薩
- But not as beautiful as you, Alissa. - ALL: Aw.
- 我愛你 - 我愛你
- I love you. - I love you.
在所有的親朋好友面前 與你並肩而立...
Being with you and in front of all of our friends and family here...
我只想說:我是這世上 最幸運的男人!
I just wanna say, I'm the luckiest man in the world!
演奏點什麼吧!
MAN: Play something!
其實,你的禮物還有一個環節!
Well, actually, there's one more part to your present!
約翰·梅爾先生來了!
It's Mr. John Mayer!
- 約翰·梅爾! - 謝謝大家,謝謝
- John Mayer! - Thank you, thank you.
大家好!
Hey, everybody!
約翰·梅爾何許人也?
Who's John Mayer?
我只想說:詹姆斯、艾麗薩 謝謝你們讓我...
I just wanna say, thank you, James and Alissa, for making me...
住口!
Shut up!
參與到你們這個特別之夜 非常感謝
A part of your special night. Thank you very much.
我要親自感謝你收購布拉德偉化學公司
I wanna thank you personally for the Bradway Chemical buy.
- 不客氣 - 我最喜歡賺錢了
- Oh, sure. Ha-ha-ha. - There's nothing I love more than making money.
不管男的女的,是人我就屌
Not even chicks. Or dudes. I fuck anything.
你們是否看過一百個女人 同時有衝動?看看這個
You ever seen 100 women get wet at the same time? Watch this.
父親們請好好對你們的女兒
SINGING Fathers, be good to your daughters.
女兒們也會同樣愛著你
Daughters will love like you do.
女孩兒開始戀愛
Girls become lovers.
最終成為人母
Who turn into mothers.
所以母親們也要 好好對待你們的女兒
So, mothers Be good to your daughters too
約翰,稍等片刻 我要彈一段
John, lay back. I'm gonna take a few bars.
嗯
MAN: Yeah.
後退! 我們是聯邦調查局!後退!
MAN: Hey! Step aside, FBI! Back up!
大家都後退!
Everybody, step aside!
- 詹姆斯·金 - 是的
- James King. - Yeah?
你因四十三宗欺詐 和三十宗貪污被捕了
MAN: You're under arrest for 43 counts of fraud and 30 counts of embezzlement.
- 那不可能 - 所有人都這麼說,把他帶走!
- That's impossible. - That's what they all say. Get him out of here!
我知道了,這是在跟我開玩笑
I know. This is some kind of joke.
如果不是開玩笑 這是最糟糕的噩夢
Because if this isn't, this is the worst nightmare imaginable.
耶!終於被抓了
Yeah! Ha-ha-ha. Finally.
- 你拍了嗎? - 沒錯!讓開!
- Are you getting this? - Shit, yeah! Get out of the way!
我發誓我根本不知道 這都是咋回事!
- I swear I don't know what any of this is about! - Mm-hm.
別擔心,兒子!我會處理的
Don't worry, son! I'll take care of it.
我們走吧
MAN: Let's go.
- 蓋爾,給我的律師打電話 - 我的派對啊!
- Gayle, call my lawyer. - My party!
看來你現在需要朋友
Looks like you could use a friend right now.
搞什麼?
What the fuck?
婊子
你被指控證券欺詐和挪用公款
The charges are securities fraud and embezzlement.
- 這些交易記錄證明了你有罪 - 我從沒見過這些,這些都是造假的!
- These transaction records prove you're guilty. - I've never seen these. These are fakes!
孩子,你要是上了法庭這麼說 你就完蛋了,認罪吧
If you go to court, they're gonna kick your ass. Take the plea.
- 爸爸! - 認罪
- Dad! - Take the plea.
一年內,你就會被釋放 大好時光還等著你呢
You'll be out in a year and in the best shape of your life.
不要,我相信司法系統會還我清白
No. I have faith that the justice system will exonerate me.
我相信陪審團將拋開他們的偏見 看到真相:
And that the jury will put aside their bias and see the truth:
也就是我沒有偷別人的錢
That I didn't steal money from people.
我不是伯納德·麥道夫
And that I am no Bernie Madoff.
詹姆斯·金詐騙案今日宣判
A verdict is expected today in the "mini-Madoff" trial of James King.
我的錢在哪兒?
ALL SHOUTING
我一無所有了!去你媽的!
I lost everything! Fuck you!
我沒幹過那樣的事!
I didn't do it!
長期以來,像你一樣的 富有白領罪犯...
JUDGE: For too long, wealthy white-collar offenders like you...
都以較輕罪行進了 安全級別最低的監獄...
have gotten a free pass with light sentences in minimum-security prison...
而努力工作的美國人則深受其害 一切都在今天結束了,金先生
while working Americans have suffered. Well, that ends today, Mr. King.
我判處你最嚴厲的處罰:
I sentence you to the harshest penalty allowed:
在安全級別最高的監獄服刑十年
Ten years in a maximum-security prison.
給你三十天來處理自己的事務
You have 30 days to get your affairs in order.
直接壓過他們!
Just run them over!
我不能去監獄,我會死在那裡
I can't go to jail. I'll die in there.
不會的,詹姆斯,因為我會安排偵查員調查此事
That's not gonna happen, James, because I'm gonna put my investigators...
馬不停蹄,直到找出真相
on this twenty-four-seven until we find out who really did this.
你要確保自己別離開本郡 讓燈一直亮著
Just stay in county lines with that thing on.
否則,美國法院執行官會很快過來
Otherwise, the U.S. Marshals will be down there pronto.
兒子,我希望你堅強點 聽到我說的話嗎?
Son, I want you to stay strong. Do you hear me?
我會的
I will.
爸爸,我會為你保持堅強
I'll be so strong for you, Dad.
入獄前30天
為什麼是我?!
Why me?
閃避!
JAOA SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
入獄前25天
我必須離開這個國家!
I have to leave the country!
這麼長時間才給我打電話 我連除毛都沒去,我感覺像一隻大猩猩
It took so long to ring me up, I had to miss my waxing appointment. I feel like a gorilla.
夏天又來了
It's summer too.
我真不敢相信我這種事發生在我頭上
ALISSA: I can't believe this is happening to me.
- 他們好像一點都不記得你了 - 謝謝,是的
- It's like they don't recognize you anymore. - Thank you. Yes.
艾麗薩!
WHISPERING Alissa!
嘿!是我,詹姆斯
Hey! It's me, James.
我知道,你在做什麼?!
I know. What are you doing?
你為何這幅德行?!
Why do you look like that?
吃你的沙拉吧
Just eat your fucking salads.
要是亂講話,我就殺了你們
I'll fucking kill you if you say anything.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨,你好 - 嗨
- Hi. Hi. - Hi.
我有個好主意
I came up with a great idea.
我們逃跑好了! 去那些沒人找得到我們的地方
Let's just run away! Some place that no one would ever think to find us.
墨西哥
Mexico.
讓我們離開這個物質世界
Let's just leave this material world behind.
住在一間一居室的小屋
Live in a one-bedroom shack.
- 噢,天啊 - 沒錯
- Oh, God. - Yes.
- 你可以在街邊小巷賣口香糖 - 啥?!
- You could sell Chiclets on the road. - What?
我們等一下再說具體事宜
Look, we'll work out the details later.
- 我們該離開這裡 - 不!
- We should get out of here. - No!
- 我已經切斷我的腳鐐了 - 不!不
- I already cut off my ankle bracelet. - No! No.
我們走吧
Let's go.
- 詹姆斯,不 - 什麼?
- James, no. - What?
- 不!我要離開你 - 為什麼?
- No! I'm leaving you. - Why?
可我以為你會永遠愛我
But I thought you loved me forever.
好吧,現在你知道了
Well, now you know.
艾麗薩
Alissa.
這裡是美國司法服務
MAN: This is the U.S. Marshal Service.
詹姆斯·金,馬上出來投降 你被逮捕了
James King, exit the building and surrender to custody immediately.
噢 ,媽的!
Oh, shit!
嘿,兄弟們,他在裡面
Hey, guys. He's in there.
你們為什麼要逮捕我?!
Why are you arresting me?
我叫埃斯·裡根杜·埃斯特班
SPEAKING IN SPANISH
我只是一名伯利茲的酒保
IN ENGLISH I am but a simple bartender from Belize.
等等,不,墨西哥
Wait, no. Mexico.
給我在提華納的律師打電話
Call my lawyer in Tijuana.
入獄前23天
媽的!
Shit!
- 他媽的那是什麼玩意兒?!下車! - 是我!是我!
- What the fuck is that?! Get off! - It's me! It's me!
- 金先生? - 是我
- Mr. King? - Yes.
你差點嚇死我,老兄
You scared the shit out of me, man.
你在後備箱裡幹嘛?!
What you doing in the trunk?
我只是想找個地方重新開始
I just needed a place to regroup.
也就是,一個新的開始
You know, fresh start.
好吧,嘿,我幫你出來,老兄
Okay. Hey. Let me help you out, man.
去你的,金!
Fuck you, King!
- 因為你我失去了所有! - 不是我幹的!
- I lost everything because of you! - I didn't do it!
媽的!
Fuck!
去他媽的,不管誰!
Fuck someone!
我他媽的!
Fuck a tit!
真他媽的!
Fuck a tit hard!
為艾倫·格林斯潘之愛
For the love of Alan Greenspan.
媽的!我的老婆泡湯了
Fuck! My life is ruined.
我敢說你已經知道 我要入獄的事了吧
I venture you've heard that I'm going to prison.
是,不僅是我,我們都知道了 只是我不想第一個提起 ,就這樣
Yeah. No, we all did. I just didn't wanna bring it up first, that's all.
別這樣,他們可能是要把你 送往某個聯邦俱樂部監獄
Come on. They're probably sending you to some Club Fed prison.
你還能繼續打你的網球和高爾夫
You'll be playing tennis and golf, you know.
- 我要被遣入聖昆丁監獄了 - 他們會把你遣入聖昆丁監獄?!
- I'm going to be attending San Quentin. - They're sending you to San Quentin?
哦
Oh.
- 什麼? - 噢,天啊!
- What? - Oh, God!
去他媽的聖昆丁監獄
They fucking in San Quentin.
所有人都很操蛋
- Oh. - Everybody gets the dick.
我不想
I don't want it.
你不會的,你最多進去三個月
You're not gonna get it. You'll be in for three months.
我得進去十年呢
I'm gonna be there for 10 years.
我靠,十年?
Goddamn! Ten years?
你怎麼這麼說?
- Oh! Oh! - Why do you say it like that?
那裡沒有我聽說的那樣糟糕吧?
It's not as bad as I've heard, is it?
如果你聽說的是群交的話,那就是了
If you heard everybody fucking, it is. That's how bad it is.
我沒聽說那種事
I didn't hear that part.
他們敢情會喚那監獄作 聖操蛋,老兄
They might as well call it San Fucking, man.
那裡實在爛透了 什麼叫糟糕,那就是糟糕
I don't wish that on my worst enemy. You talking about bad? That's bad.
你該知道的
You should know.
抱歉提醒你了
I'm sorry to remind you.
你們在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
你坐過牢
Well, the fact that you went to prison.
我坐過牢?
The fact that I went to prison?
對,你坐過牢
Yes. Look, you did your time.
你償還了對社會的債務
You paid your debt. And we as society...
社會應該歡迎你回來,真的
should welcome you back, and we do.
你我是同路中人
You and I are exactly the same.
只是你沒有選舉權
Except you can't vote, ever.
趁我脾氣還沒變得更糟 金先生,趕緊痛快點告訴我
Just before I get to another level of anger, Mr. King, tell me for giggles...
你怎麼知道我坐過牢?
- how do you know I went to prison? - It's simple.
其實很簡單 我只是做了點統計分析,是這樣的:
- Statistical analysis is what I do. - Here's the deal:
每三個黑人中就會有一個 進過監獄
One out of three black men will find themselves incarcerated during their lifetime.
- 想一下比薩,可以吧? - 好
- Imagine a pizza, okay? - Okay.
有那麼三片
There are three pieces.
三片黑色的
Three black pieces.
這三片比薩中有一片會在 某個時刻被扔進牢房裡去
One of those pieces of pizza will be thrown in jail at some point during it's life.
我跟你說說我的統計分析
You know what? Let me give you my statistical analysis.
你會去聖昆丁監獄,可以百分之百確定
You going to San Quentin. There's 100 percent chance...
你會成為某人的小婊子 會有十年時間一直這樣
- that you're gonna be somebody's bitch. - Ten years of this:
你知道是什麼嗎?
- You know what that is? - Mm-mm.
會有一個大屁股黑人 光顧你蒼白的翹臀
A big-ass black man on your pale white ass.
你會說:“不!我受夠了! 別這樣!夠了”
YOU: "No! I don't want any more! Stop! That's enough."
太晚了,他走之後 下一個傢伙又來了
Too late. He done tagged the next guy in.
就像只兔子,而你不想再要他了
That's like a rabbit. You don't want him no more...
因此現在就有別人想劫你色
so now here comes the guy that wants to rub your face.
“我喜歡他的頭髮” 你都能感受到他的喘息
"I like his hair." He's breathing on you.
太噁心了,不過你猜怎麼著? 你可以過十年這種日子!
That's disgusting. But guess what? You can look forward to 10 years of it!
要是我集結所有的小婊子們...
What if I speak to all the bitches and we organize...
成為一個聯盟,並立場堅定地 說:“夠了!”
form a union, and we put our feet down and say, "Enough!"
- 我們人數會比他們多 - 其實我們沒他們多
- There's gotta be more of us than them. - There's not.
你所受的一切都是你應得的 先生,祝你能活下來
You deserve everything you're getting. Good luck on survival, sir.
希望你能管好自己!
Better luck on handling yourself!
等等!等等!等等!別走 求你別走,我會請你幫忙
Wait! Wait! Wait! Don't leave. Don't leave, please. I could use your help.
幫你什麼?!
Help you with what?
幫我別成為別人的婊子
Help me to not be someone's bitch.
你指望我幫你?! 我該教你點什麼?!
You expect me to help you? I'm supposed to teach you what?
怎樣避免這些:
How to prevent this:
- 好吧,打住 - 你可以訓練我
- All right, stop. - You could train me.
你可以做我這奧德賽的雅典娜
You could be the Athena to my Odysseus.
夥計,我都不知道 你說的是啥意思!
I don't even know what the fuck that is, man!
我可以花錢請你
I could pay you.
你要什麼都滿足你
Whatever it takes.
我要三萬美金
I need $30,000.
沒問題
- Done. - Oh...
好
Okay.
對,嗯
Yup. Yeah.
- 很好 - 沒錯
- Fantastic. - All right.
你在幹嘛?
What are you doing?
我只知道這兩個
I only know these two.
你要幹什麼?
What are you trying to do?
- 握手?你想跟我握手? - 噢,就是普通的
- Shake? You wanna shake my hand? - Oh, regular.
- 成交,成交 - 很好
- It's a deal. We got a deal. - Excellent.
- 謝謝你,達內爾 - 早上見,囚徒
- Thank you, Darnell. - I'll see you in the morning, convict.
你在幹嘛?那是什麼?
What are you doing? What is that?
- 試著來幹這件事 - 不
- Trying to do this thing. - No.
- 握手,沒事的 - 好
- Shake. It's fine. - Okay.
金先生,不,我來吧
Mr. King, no. I got that.
- 好,沒問題 - 非常感謝
- All right. No problem. - I appreciate it.
非常感謝
I appreciate it.
好!謝謝你!
Yes! Thank you!
謝天謝地
Thank you, Jesus!
我就知道我會有出頭之日
I knew it! I knew my day would come.
老子要有房子了
I'm getting the house.
I'm getting the house. Unh!
寶貝,這完全說不通啊
Babe. This does not make any sense.
他幹嘛要雇你?
Why would he hire you?
- 因為他覺得我在牢裡呆過 - 看,這部分我不明白
- Because he thinks I went to prison, babe. - That's the part I don't get.
- 你幹嘛要告訴他? - 我沒有把那個告訴他,他自己猜的
- Why would you tell him that? - I didn't. He assumed that.
- 他猜的? - 沒錯!
- He assumed it? - Yes!
那你因為什麼讓他猜你進過監獄?
So what reason did you give him to assume that you went to jail?
我是個黑人
I was being black.
- 這太可惡了 - 我不知道這怎麼就可惡了
- This is nuts. - Okay. I don't get what's nuts to you.
三十天內,我們就能拿到錢 這房子就是我們的,有問題嗎?
In 30 days, we'll have the money, the house will be ours. What is the problem?
問題是,他永遠不會相信 你進過監獄
The problem is he is never going to believe that you went to jail.
聽著,寶貝,我是你妻子 所以我還是直說吧
Look, babe. I am your wife, so I will put it to you straight.
你完全不像個混混
You are not exactly a thug.
沒吃過雞肉,還沒看過雞跑啊?
I don't have to be a thug to portray a thug. Okay?
老實說,我所要做的就是改變我的聲音 說話聲音低沉一點
Honestly, all I gotta do is change my voice, talk a little deeper.
這樣說話,非常刻板 他就已經認為我是了
IN DEEP VOICE Talk like this and be every stereotype he already thinks I am.
現在,我就是個混混了 現在就是
Right now, I'm thugging. This is thugging.
寶貝,這方面你太棒了
You're so good at it, sweetie.
晚安
Have a good night.
- 賤人!別從我身邊走開! - 你剛對我說什麼?!
- Bitch! Don't walk away from me! - What the hell did you just say to me?
- 老婆,住手 - 你腦子有毛病?!
- IN NORMAL VOICE Girl, stop. Stop! - What is wrong with you?
那是什麼?!我愛你!我在入戲!
What is that? I love you! I was playing!
- 賤人 - 啥?!
- Bitch. - What?
我什麼都沒說!
- I didn't say nothing! - Oh.
我什麼都沒說
Man, I didn't say nothing.
你想看《戀戀筆記本》嗎?
You wanna watch The Notebook?
- 我愛你和瑪凱拉 - 嗯,我也愛你,晚安
- I love you and Makayla. - Yeah, I love you too. Good night.
午夜秀場 主持人吉米·法倫
這裡是馬丁·克拉克的語音郵箱
WOMAN ON RECORDING: You've reached the mailbox of Martin Clark.
請在提示音後留下信息
Please leave a message after the tone.
嗨,爸爸在嗎?
Hi, Dad?
我是詹姆斯
It's James.
我想問問調查員那兒有信兒沒
Just wondering if there's any word from the investigators.
依然愛你
I still love you.
謝謝你,再見
Thank you. Bye.
我現在聽說了你 一件很瘋狂的事情,這傢伙是詹姆斯·金嗎?
Now, I heard a crazy story about you. This guy James King?
我聽說你在他被捕的聚會上 還表演來著
And I heard that you played at the party where he got arrested.
對,我不知道我在給個怪物表演
Yeah. I had no idea that I was performing for a monster.
我都不知該怎麼解釋 怎麼能拿那種人的錢
I don't know how to explain what it's like to take money from someone like that.
你真的想把錢還回去...
It makes you wanna give it back to them...
可這樣會更糟糕 因為這筆錢就歸他了
except that would be worse because then they'd have it.
就是那種無助的感覺下 我覺得我們的創作被金錢把持...
And it's that whole helpless feeling that I have about our creative process being monetized...
那感覺給了我寫這首歌的靈感...
and that's what inspired me to write this song...
這首歌在今天午夜 就能在iTunes上下載了
which is actually available on iTunes tonight at midnight.
- 前提是我還能演奏它的話 - 很好
- If I can play it. - Great.
*我沒有千里眼
SINGING I can't see through walls.
*也沒有讀心術
And I can't read your mind.
*但如果我能覺察到
But if I did I'd find.
*那個詹姆斯·金是個大壞蛋
That man James King is a great big turd.
*或者說是個小賤人
I mean the small, small kinds.
*但是那混蛋詹姆斯會
But that **** James.
*手抵在大牢裡墻面壁
Will fall Hands against the prison wall.
*和給別人亂搞口交
Choking on a mouthful of balls.
*他會做的一口好活
He'll be choking on A mouthful of balls
我並不願意這麼講 不過這確是首好歌
I hate to admit it, but it's a good song.
很好,謝謝約翰·梅爾
FALLON: Okay, very nice. John Mayer, everybody.
現在我要夢見蛋蛋了
Now I'm gonna be dreaming about balls.
嘿,羅素
DARNELL: Hey, Russell.
這是達內爾
It's Darnell.
夥計,是你的表哥 表哥啊,達內爾
Your cousin. Your cousin, Darnell, man.
嘿,聽著,羅素...
Hey, listen, Russell...
我給你五百美金,你告訴我 監獄是什麼樣子的吧
how would you like to make $500 just for telling me what prison was like.
其實我不想說 羅素,我不該說那些的
Well, I don't wanna say that. Russell, I shouldn't have to say that.
為什麼?!怎麼...?
For what?! What is...?
好吧,行
Fine. Fine.
我是個人見人罵的混賬東西
I'm a Cliff Huxtable pussy-looking motherfucker.
不!我甚至都沒穿卡其褲
No! I'm not even wearing khakis.
羅素,你能幫我一下 我跟你說的事情嗎?從頭開始吧
Russell, can you please just help me, what I'm asking you for? Just start from the beginning.
不,不行,要從頭,從頭開始 從進大牢的第一天開始
No, no. Like, the beginning, the beginning. Like, the first day of prison.
從第一天就開始了?!
On the first day?
不用暖場嗎?
Oh. There's no warm-up?
太傷感了
That's sad.
羅素,很抱歉 我剛才是不是聽到了槍聲?
Russell, I'm sorry, did I just hear a gunshot?
你該走了,好,再見
You gotta go. Okay. Bye.
入獄前22天
準備好了,媽媽...?
Ready, mother...?
準備好了,媽媽...? 準備好了,媽媽...?
Ready, mother...? Ready, mother...?
這就對了,快點
That's it, that's it. Ahem.
來了!
Coming!
麗塔,瑪凱拉 新房子,學校不錯
Rita, Makayla, new house, good school.
準備好了嗎,你個混賬東西?
You ready, motherfucker?
等一下!
Just a second!
有人嗎?
Hello?
準備好了嗎,混賬東西?!
- You ready, motherfucker?! - Aah!
- 噢,疼死我了! - 這是防狼噴霧劑,賤人!
- Oh, it burns! - Pepper spray, bitch!
第一誡:你一定要 有所防備,知道嗎?
RULE NUMBER ONE: You always be on guard, okay?
因為在裡面總是 會有人想要折騰你!
On the inside, there's somebody on every corner to fuck you up!
賤人,監獄學堂開始了!你已經陷進去了
Prison school is in session, bitch! You already failing.
真高興我能請到你 這正是我需要的
I'm so glad I hired you. This is just what I need.
好,下一步是什麼?
Okay. What's next?
這怎麼...?!這兒住著 多少混賬東西?!
What the...?! How many motherfuckers live here?!
好吧,我們開始吧
All right. Let's get started.
就這兒,是我的牢獄準備教程
This right here is my prison readiness program.
要是你跟著說明做 我敢保證你肯定能在監獄裡活下來
If you follow this guide and do exactly what I say you will survive in prison.
牢獄準備教程
“保險箱”
JAMES: "Keistering."
- 保險箱是什麼東西? - 慢點!你還沒準備好
- What's keistering? - Slow down! You ain't ready for that.
你是個老師
You're the teacher.
我只是想讓你知道,我願不惜任何代價 在監獄裡活下來
And I just want you to know I'll do whatever it takes to survive and get my life back.
很好,因為我要 給你打個預防針:
That's good, because let me tell you something:
你要受你從來沒受過的罪
You're gonna have to work harder than you ever worked before.
其實,我還在哈佛商學院上學的時候 面對過很多棘手的問題
Back when I was in Harvard Business School, I was facing some pretty long odds.
不過我都把問題解決 而且成功了
But I buckled down and I succeeded.
我在哈佛的時候 你有沒有因為掛科被強姦過?
When you was at Harvard, did you ever get raped for failing a test?
我覺得那是耶魯的傳統
I think that's more of a Yale thing.
- “耶魯” - 抱歉
- "Yale." - I'm sorry.
你丫閉嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
從現在開始 這不再是你的房子了
Now from this point on, this ain't your house no more.
- 這是聖昆丁!你明白嗎? - 明白
- This San Quentin! You understand me? - Okay.
從現在開始這會是你的牢房
DARNELL: From now on this will be your cell.
沒有我的許可 你不能離開這個屋子
You do not leave this room without my permission.
沒問題
It's good.
- 先生,你就睡這兒吧 - 繼續,我們沒時間玩鬧了
- For you to sleep on, se?or. - Go on, we ain't got time for games.
去樓上,把這地方變成監獄
Go upstairs, turn this place into prison.
我很願意報答你的恩德
It will be our pleasure to repay you for your many kindnesses.
把那個放在 有小雞雞的雕像前面
Put that in there in front of the statues with the dicks.
詹姆斯,聽著
James, listen to me.
要想在監獄裡活下來 關鍵是要遵守一個簡單的問題:
The key to survival in prison lies in the following simple questions:
你是不是夠強硬? 你能管住你自己嗎?
Are you hard? And can you handle yourself?
其實,這是樂觀主義轉瞬即逝的時刻 因為那答案是確鑿的
Well, this is a rare moment for optimism because the answer to that is a resounding yes.
好,那很好,讓我看一下你的瘋狗臉
That's good. Let me see what your mad-dog face look like.
- 不好意思,什麼瘋狗? - 你這個瘋狗啊!
- I'm sorry. What's a mad dog? - You a mad dog!
- 噢,糟了 - 你丫是個什麼玩意,黑鬼?
- Oh, shit. - What's your what, nigga?
- 你想要什麼就拿什麼! - 讓我看看那個!
- Take whatever you want! - Let me see that!
不!
No!
- 別!求你了! - 放馬出來吧
- Stop! I beg of you! - Like a pit bull with no leash.
那就是瘋狗
That's a mad dog.
哇,我覺得你非常勝任這事
Wow. I knew you were the right guy for the job.
在監獄裡,瘋狗臉對你的生存至關重要 你明白嗎,詹姆斯?
In prison, a mad-dog face is essential to your survival. Do you understand me, James?
所以現在要做的是,我的臉上要有一種 我肯定可以打死你的表情
So the idea is that I make a face that conveys the fact that I'd have no problem hurting you.
沒錯,現在給我來個那表情,我看一下
Exactly what it is. Now, convey that shit. Let me see it.
好
Okay. Ahem.
太糟糕了
- That's terrible. - Ha, ha.
不,太慫了 夥計,要有怒火,你要讓我看到你的怒火
No, that's horrible, man. Anger. You gotta show me anger.
- 你笑什麼? - 我沒笑,我很緊張
- Why you smiling? - I'm not smiling. I'm tense and I'm agitated.
別這樣啊,老兄!
Come on, man!
啊?那就是你的瘋...就這?!
- Unh! - That's your mad... That's it?!
- 你的未婚妻離你而去了 - 沒錯
- Your fiancée left you. - That's right!
- 你對此高興嗎? - 不高興
- You happy about that? - No.
那就來點怒火!她要離開你了?! 她現在在幹什麼?!
Then get mad! She gonna leave you? What is she doing?
她可能在一輛車的後座 給別人吹簫
She probably on her knees sucking somebody dick in the back seat of a truck.
表現出來...
Show...
詹姆斯
James.
快點,加油
Oh. Oh. Come on. Come on.
- 我好想她 - 你他媽在幹嘛啊,詹姆斯?
- I miss her so much. - What the fuck are you doing, James?
我在給你看傷心狗的表情
I'm sad-dogging you.
- 詹姆斯 - 你覺得這麼幹能行嗎?
- James? - You think that's a strategy that could work?
我不覺得這麼幹能行
No. I don't think it's a strategy that could work.
嘿,都聽著 我非常傷心
Hey, listen up, everyone. I'm extremely sad.
別對我性騷擾 我已經很傷心了
Please don't sexually assault me. I'm already too sad.
嘿,夥計們,我的心已經被強姦了
Hey, fellas. My heart's already been raped.
等一下,我不想這樣做了 我們走吧,好吧?
I don't wanna do this anymore. Let's move on. Okay?
我們不學瘋狗了 詹姆斯,你會打架嗎?
We're moving on from the mad dog. James, can you fight?
沒問題
Absolutely.
迴避,迴避
SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
什麼?
What?
你還得換衣服才能做這事?
You had to change your clothes for this?
入口
SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
夥計,你他媽在幹嘛?
What the fuck are you doing, man?
這叫卡波衛勒舞
It's called Capoeira.
這是巴西人的武術
It's a Brazilian martial art.
不過別被它花哨的動作愚弄了
But don't be fooled by its beauty and grace.
它其實挺致命的
It's actually quite deadly.
很致命嗎?
This is deadly?
That's deadly?
戳
- Stab. - Ow.
- 我戳 - 停下
- Stab. - Stop.
- 戳戳 - 獄卒!獄卒!
- Stab. Stab. - Guards! Guards!
不停地戳,戳,戳!
- Stabbity-stab, stab, stab! - Ow. Ow!
夥計,你在幹嘛?!
The fuck are you doing, man?
這鳥東西沒法讓你 在聖昆丁監獄活下來!
Shit ain't gonna save you in San Quentin!
好吧,或許那個不行 不過你沒見過我的連環踢
Well, that may not, but you haven't seen my Bên??o kick.
- 你的什麼?! - 我的連環踢
- Your what?! - My Bên??o kick.
我踢!
SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
看你這傻帽做了什麼 戳!
Look what your dumb ass done did. Stab.
- 戳 - 我死了
- Stab. - I'm dead.
戳戳戳戳
Stab, stab, stab, stab.
入獄前21天
你太壞了
You're so bad.
奧,詹姆斯,我得告訴你 我不敢想你要經歷些什麼
James. I gotta tell ya. I just can't imagine what you must be going through.
跟你說話真好
It is so nice to talk to you.
- 那調查者有什麼最新消息? - 調查者?
JAMES: What's the latest from the investigators? The investigators?
- 中國黑客啊,他們挺確定的 - 嘿!
- Chinese hackers. They're pretty sure. - DARNELL: Hey!
我知道我沒瘋 我沒跟你說不能用電話嗎?放下電話
I know I'm not crazy. Didn't I tell you to get off the phone? Get off the phone.
- 嘿,你在跟誰說話? - 是達內爾,他正在幫我
- Hey, who are you talking to? - It's Darnell. He's helping me.
你沒時間了!
Your time is up!
- 我要走了,我會給你打回來的 - 掛掉!
- I gotta go. I'll call you back. - Hang it up!
- 真希望我能有更多時間打電話 - 掛電話!
- If I get more phone time. - Hang it up!
那對我很重要!
That was important to me!
告訴你吧,要是你前面有一排 憤怒的囚犯在等著用電話...
When you got a line of inmates waiting to use the phone...
你千萬別把他們惹毛,詹姆斯
you do not wanna piss them off, James.
我要弄死你,詹姆斯先生!
I'm going to fuck you up, Mr. James!
羅莎!
Rosa!
在操場上你給我多留神
You watch your back on the yard.
婊子
SPEAKS IN SPANISH
我不是婊子
I'm not a puto.
很好
Great.
- 好,我們遇到麻煩了 - 什麼麻煩?
- All right. We got a problem. - ATTORNEY: What's that?
詹姆斯在跟人說話
James is talking to somebody.
不,不,他相信你
No, no, he trusts you.
- 他從不會根據事實進行推理的 - 不,別這樣,彼得!別這樣!
- He'll never put two and two together. - No, stop it!
- 這是你的錯! - 什麼?
- This is your fault! - What?
你不應該讓他接受認罪協議,對吧?
Well, you couldn't get him to take the plea deal.
他不該進監獄,而你應該讓他 有三十天不在那兒,四處走走...
Instead of him going to prison, you got him 30 days to be out there, running around...
把事情搞砸!
fucking things up!
我不得不讓這件事體面些 不能收場得太潦草吧,沒事的
I had to make it look good. You throw a fight, you don't go down in the first round. It's fine.
我不想讓他在那兒跟某個人 玩偵探遊戲
I don't want him out there, playing detective with somebody.
你要好生照看好 我前準女婿,明白嗎?
You keep an eye on my ex-future son-in-law, would ya?
- 然後找出誰是達內爾 - 我這就去
- And find out who this Darnell is. - I'm on it. Right away.
這就對了
There you go.
好,詹姆斯,聽著 你要去裡面打一架,好吧?
All right, James. Look, you're gonna get in a fight on the inside. Okay?
你並不一定非要贏 但是你要給這些傢伙看看
You don't need to win, but you need to show these guys...
你是敢回擊的,夥計,你得習慣打架 看見那邊的幾個傢伙了嗎?
that you're not afraid to fight back. Get used to fighting. See those guys over there?
- 看見了 - 我要你去那兒,然後從裡面選一個跟他打一架
- Yes. - Go over there and fight one of them.
瘋了吧!
That's insane!
他們都那麼壯 都可以把我虐成渣了
They're behemoths. They would break my spine.
這些類型的傢伙就是 你將在聖昆丁監獄遇到的
Those are the type of guys you're gonna see in San Quentin.
所以,老兄,你得克服恐懼,我要你到那裡 一月內揍倒那個大塊頭
So you gotta shake that fear. I want you to go and punch that big-ass dude in the mouth.
哦,老天,我的心臟在砰砰跳
Oh, my God. My heart is pounding.
好吧
Okay.
嘿,夥計們
Hey, guys.
你他媽是誰?
Who the fuck are you, man?
我要打你
I wanna fight you.
什麼?
What?
你選了個錯誤的日子來公園
You picked the wrong day to come to the park.
- 老兄,這是什麼玩笑嗎? - 你以前看過瘋狗臉嗎?
- Is this some kind of joke, man? - You ever been mad-dogged before?
你馬上就要嘗到被扁的滋味了 混蛋玩意
You about to get some right now, motherfucker.
這他媽是什麼?
What the fuck is that, man?
這是你陰莖的大小
It's the size of your dick.
我會折斷它,讓你吞下去
I'm gonna break it off, make you eat it.
你用這個找幹你媽?
You fuck your mother with that dick?
你怎麼知道我媽媽? 你不認識我媽媽
How do you know my mama?! You don't know my mama.
不
Oh, no.
上啊!揍他!揍他!
- Aah! Aah! Aah! MAN: Come on! - Get him! Get him!
回來這裡,婊子!
Get back here, bitch!
哦,不!別打我軀幹!
Oh, no! Please don't hurt my body! Aah!
不!我的身體!
No! My body!
救命!
Help me!
我的脊椎要斷了!
You're breaking my spine!
入獄前二十天
高壓電 請勿接近 我的網球場怎麼了?
What happened to my tennis court?
詹姆斯,這裡不再是網球場了 從現在開始,這裡是操場
You will no longer refer to this area as a tennis court. From this point on, this is the yard.
聽清楚,詹姆斯 操場是監獄裡最危險致命的地方
Understand something, James. The yard is the most deadliest part of prison.
這裡是你能享受幾分鐘珍貴的 新鮮空氣和陽光的地方,你明白嗎?
It's where you get your few precious minutes of fresh air and sunlight. Understand?
新鮮空氣
Fresh air.
有多少次我呼吸著新鮮空氣,聞著 薰衣草香,認為這都是理所當然的?
How many times did I breathe in clean air, fragrant with lavender, and take it for granted?
詹姆斯,我不在乎多少次,一點也不在乎
James, I don't give a fuck how many times. I don't give a shit.
- 我只是說說 - 閉嘴,詹姆斯
- I'm just saying. - Shut up, James.
你行動要小心,因為一旦你在錯誤的 時間踏入錯誤的地方...
You gotta step carefully because if you step in the wrong place...
你就完蛋了 對於像你這樣不會打架的人
you'll end up in the wrong territory. For a person like you that can't fight...
詹姆斯,這不是好事,糟糕透頂
it's not a good thing, James. It's not a good thing at all.
老兄,你現在在僅限黑人活動的區域 給你兩秒鐘滾出這裡
Right now, you in the brothers-only section. You got two seconds to get out.
- 在你挨揍之前 - 好吧,達尼爾
- Before you get mollywhopped. - Okay, Darnell.
- 誰是達尼爾? - 你是
- Who's Darnell?! - You are.
我的名字是勒羅伊!
My name is Leroy!
- 對,我建議你走開,白人小子,走! - 好,我在走
- Yeah, I suggest you walk, white boy. Walk! - All right. I'm walking.
- 轉身,走! - 我在走
- Turn around and walk! - I'm walking.
- 嘿,老兄 - 什麼事?
- IN SPANISH ACCENT Hey, ése. - What?
- 你有麻煩了,美國佬 - 達尼爾,你在幹嘛?
- You got a problem, gringo? - Darnell, what are you doing?
達尼爾?老兄,誰是達尼爾? 你看的是卡洛斯
Darnell? Who's Darnell, ése? You're looking at Carlos.
我建議你走回你來的地方,埃塞 要不你就有麻煩了
I suggest you walk wherever you came from, ése, before you have a problem.
- 我只是試圖離開立刻這片區域 - 好吧,老兄
- I was trying to leave that area. - You need to go back...
- 你最好回去黑鬼那裡 - 去找勒羅伊?
- over there with the negros, ése. - With Leroy?
你給我回去黑鬼那裡! 因為那才是你該在的地方
You go back over there with the negros! That's where you belong.
- 我沒看見任何人 - 你該和黑鬼呆在一起
- I don't see anyone. - You belong with the Negros.
- 走 - 馬上
- Go. - I'm going.
- 操你媽卡洛斯,你說黑鬼?! - 他說的,我沒有
- IN NORMAL VOICE Fuck you calling a negro?! - He was. I wasn't.
我警告你,卡洛斯! 這坨狗屎歸你們那邊!
I told you, Carlos! Keep that shit over there on your side!
- 把這個美國佬帶走! - 我要和你走!
- Take the Yankee with you! - I'll go with you!
嘿,我不想帶著他 我不想帶著他
IN SPANISH ACCENT Hey, I don't want him.
他喜歡黑鬼,你帶他走
He's a negro lover. You take him.
混賬東西!你再說!
IN NORMAL VOICE Motherfucker! Say something else, bro!
嘿!嘿!我向上帝發誓 老兄,我發誓我要宰了你
IN SPANISH ACCENT Hey! Hey, I swear to God. I swear to God, I'll cut you,ése.
- 握手言和吧 - - 這裡沒有握手這回事,美國佬
- Let's just shake hands. - There is no shaking hands, gringo.
- 友誼 - 回去你該待的地方
- Friendship. - Go back where you belong.
我不知道該呆在哪
I don't know where I belong.
離他遠點,我來罩他
IN FEMININE VOICE Leave him alone. I'll keep him.
你跟著我
You belong with me.
- 你是誰? - 我是但丁
- Who are you? - I'm Dante.
你幹嘛不離他遠點,卡洛斯! 離他遠點,勒羅伊!
Why don't you leave him alone, Carlos! Leave him alone, Leroy!
- 你是娘們嗎? - 如果你想,我就是
- Are you a woman? - I am if you want me to be.
我不想這樣
I don't want that.
- 好吧,我知道你是什麼東西了 - 我來幫你掏掏兜
- Okay, I know what you are. - Let me hold your pocket.
- 我來幫你掏掏兜 - 好吧
- Let me hold your pocket. - All right.
他歸我了!他是我的,勒羅伊!
I claimed him! He mine, Leroy!
婊子!限你兩秒帶著他的兜滾蛋,二!
IN NORMAL VOICE Bitch, you got two seconds to let his fucking pocket go. Two!
- 混蛋!兩秒到了,婊子! - 別打女人!
- Motherfucker! You got two seconds! - Don't hit a woman!
- 我要揍得你屁滾尿流! - 別打女人!
- Gonna knock your ass out! - Don't hit a woman!
你不想要我的人
IN FEMININE VOICE You don't want my pocket.
你不想要,那又如何?! 為什麼我不能高興?
You don't want it. So what? Why can't I be happy?
嘿,老兄,我討厭你,還有 我和兄弟們面前的這坨狗屎
IN SPANISH ACCENT Hey, ése. I don't like you and this domestic shit in front of my crew.
你認為我喜歡?
You think I like it?
老兄,你他媽帶著他滾到別處去 聽見了嗎?
You need to fucking take it somewhere else, ése, huh?
美國佬,你帶著 你那骯髒的婊子滾到別處去
Gringo, you take you and your dirty bitch elsewhere.
- 我會去那裡 - 別說我髒,卡洛斯
- I'll go over there. - IN FEMININE VOICE Don't call me dirty.
我們在一起時我不髒 我那時不髒,不是嗎?
I wasn't dirty when you was up in it. I wasn't dirty then, was I?
那時是你很髒,現在你也髒,婊子
IN SPANISH ACCENT You were dirty then. You're dirty now.
- 那又如何?那又如何?他沒抱怨 - 你該接受試煉
- IN FEMININE VOICE He ain't complaining. - You should get tested.
不,我沒有抱怨 因為我們還沒有任何互動
No, I'm not complaining because we have yet to have any sort of interaction.
- 今晚會是我們的時間 - 不,我們不會,今晚不會發生
- Tonight will be our night. - No. Tonight won't happen.
- 成為我的白衣騎士,拯救我 - 別抱希望
- Be my white knight. Save me. - Don't get your hopes up.
讓我帶著你,帶你到安全的地方
Let me ride you. Let me ride you into safety.
不!這讓我不太舒服 放開我!勒羅伊會生氣的
No! I don't feel comfortable with that. Let go of me! Leroy is going to be upset.
- 我知道你會回來 - 混賬!混帳!
- I knew you were coming back. - IN NORMAL VOICE Motherfucker!
我知道你會回來
I knew you were coming back.
你要把我弄瘋了,混蛋玩意
You making me mad, motherfucker!
- 我什麼也沒做! - 我要踢你的屁股,白人小子!
- I'm not doing anything! - I'm about to whoop your ass, white boy!
- 我只不過是站在這裡 - 你不是,你搶了我的婊子
- I'm just standing here. - No, you not. You got my bitch!
- 正想找個地方 - 我是你的老婊子
- Trying to figure out a place... - IN FEMININE VOICE I'm your old bitch.
我們就像斑馬
We're like zebras.
- 我們不像斑馬 - 我們像斑馬
- We're not like a zebra. - We are like a zebra. You're my...
你是在逼我抱你 我不知道怎麼會這樣
Somehow you're getting me to hug you, and I don't know how that's happening.
就是這樣!就是這樣,美國佬 我向天發誓,我受夠了,我要捅死你
IN SPANISH ACCENT That's it! That's it, gringo. I swear, I'm getting sick of this shit. I'll stab you.
卡洛斯,我仍迷惑於這個謎題裡 你扮演的什麼角色
I'm still confused as to what piece you are in this puzzle, Carlos.
等等!等等,提問,提問
Hold on! Hold on. Question, question.
這裡有法國黑幫嗎?
Are there any French gangs?
我會講法語,不太流利,但是我會...
I speak French. I'm not fluent, but I can...
我叫詹姆斯
SPEAKING IN FRENCH
請問,我能入幫嗎?
IN ENGLISH Can I join the gang, s'il vous pla?t?
你知道嗎,詹姆斯?你不會打架 鑒於你不會打架這個事實...
IN NORMAL VOICE You know what? You can't fight. Since you can't fight...
我只有一個選擇,就是鍛煉你的身體
I'm left with one choice, and that's to get your stupid ass in shape.
上帝!你不會成功的
God! You're failing.
在四十英尺遠處有家頂尖的健身房
JAMES: I've got a state-of-the-art gym 40 feet away.
聖昆丁監獄可沒健身房
Ain't no gyms in San Quentin.
入獄前十九天 把我扭起來,婊子!把我扭起來!
Curl me, bitch! Curl me!
入獄前十七天 也許我該從嬰兒開始舉
Maybe I should start with a baby at higher reps.
嘿!嘿,你!
Hey! Hey, you!
- 我要揍你 - 白痴,你說什麼?
- I wanna fight you. - What'd you say, dickhead?
我要揍你,混蛋
I wanna fight you, asshole.
入獄前十六天 我們休息一下吧
JAMES: Let's just rest here.
入獄前十四天
GRUNTING
看著他的臉,他看起來馬上 就要被搞乾翻了
Look at his face. He looks like he's getting fucked right now.
上啊!
Come on!
你最好別摔了我!該死!
You better not drop me! Goddamn it!
抱歉,先生,我不想打擾你 但我需要揍你
Excuse me, sir. I hate to bother you, but I need to fight you.
我參加過越戰!
I was in Nam!
我愛死它了!
And I fucking loved it!
詹姆斯,你得還手啊!
James, you gotta throw something back!
達尼爾!
JAMES: Darnell!
救我!
JAMES: Save me!
入獄前十二天 加州監獄 所有犯人注意,五分鐘後關門
DARNELL OVER PA: Attention inmates, lockdown in five minutes.
千萬別做傻事
And don't try any stupid shit.
他們把我的院子怎麼了?
JAMES WHISPERING: What did they do to my yard?
沒有哪個監獄能關住詹姆斯·金
No prison can hold James King.
- 有人越獄,詹姆斯跑了! - 我操!
- We got a runner. Mr. James is running! - Oh, fuck me!
有人越獄
CECELIO SHOUTS IN SPANISH
你現在是我的了,婊子!
You're in my world now, bitch!
媽的,可惡!
Mother... Shit!
你永遠不能活著出去
You're never getting out alive! Ha, ha.
操你媽的!
Fuck a bag of tits!
放狗!
Release the dogs!
什麼?放狗?
What? Dogs?
你無處可逃了,詹姆斯先生
There's nowhere to run, Mr. James.
你真是不知天高地厚啊
You don't know when to quit, Mr. James.
你連西西裡奧和吉娃娃的掌心都逃不出
You couldn't get past Cecelio and some Chihuahuas.
你要如何逃出聖昆丁監獄? 別再浪費時間了
Tell me how you gonna escape San Quentin. Stop wasting my time, James.
這就是非法翻越圍欄的下場,知道嗎?
That's what happens when you try to jump a fence illegally. Hm?
老兄,你的訓練不太順利
Your training's not going well, man.
我是說,坦白講,我覺得 你沒有盡百分百的努力
Frankly, I don't feel like you're giving me 100 percent.
作為你的獄前教育專家,我很擔憂
And as your incarceration expert, that concerns me.
因為我的工作是讓你做好獄前準備
Because it's my job to prepare you.
幸運的是,我有個計劃
Fortunately, I got a plan.
哦,感謝上帝,太好了
Oh, thank God. Oh, that's good.
- 你要學會如何接受口交 - 什麼?!
- You're gonna learn how to suck dick. - What?!
哦,上帝
Oh, God.
聽好了,我說你要學會如何口交
Listen up. I said I want you to learn how to suck dick.
我聽到了!
I heard you!
- 這就是你的計劃? - 是的
- That's your plan? - Yes.
我要說的是,如果命運把這個陰莖 放進你嘴裡,你就得接受口交
All I'm saying is that when life puts a dick in your mouth, you make dickade.
“口交”不比陰莖好聽多少
"Dickade" doesn't sound like a significant improvement over dick.
退一萬步講,詹姆斯! 我知道我在說什麼
Bottom line, James! I know what I'm talking about.
- 我們說的是活下來 - 我明白
- We're talking about survival. - I understand.
- 這就是你活下來的原因,對嗎? - 不,你閉嘴,不,這不是
- Because that's how you survived. Right? - No, you shut your mouth. No, it is not.
我靠這些活下來
I survived with these.
- 雙手擼絕活 - 不,不是!我用拳頭打架
- Dual hand jobs. - No. No! I kill with these.
這就是你和我的區別 因此你需要去做口交
That's the difference between me and you. Hence, why you need to suck a dick.
來吧,老兄
Come on, man.
我要去哪裡找個人去...?
Where am I gonna find someone who...?
我們在伊瓦爾斯酒吧
We're at the lvars Brasserie.
看你周圍
Look around you.
這裡是洛杉磯排名第一 基佬釣凱子的地方
This is L.A.'s number-one gay hookup scene.
- 連續三年被譽為“調情聖地” - 我該怎麼說?用什麼措辭?
- Voted "Flirtiest Brunch" three years in a row. - What do I say? What do I literally say?
你就禮貌地說,“我想為你口交”
You say, "I wanna suck your dick." Politely.
嘿,嗨,我叫詹姆斯 你介意我替你吹個簫嗎?
Hey, hi. I'm James. You mind if I could give you a little head?
- 嘿,我是詹姆斯 - 我想為你口交
- Hey, I'm James. - I wanna suck your dick.
- 我想為你口交 - 就是這樣!繼續!
- I wanna suck your dick. - There you go! Just dive in!
- 他們就是這麼幹的 - 有人拒絕怎麼辦?
- That's what they do. - What if someone says no?
沒人會說不,這是客觀事實
He ain't gonna say no. It's a scientific fact.
誰說的?
According to who?
口交百科網!這有什麼關係呢?
Dickapedia! Why do you care?
- 這網站是真的嗎? - 不,詹姆斯,那是...站起來
- Is that a real site? - No. James, it's a... Get up.
去那個酒吧,那個傢伙 那裡的那個傢伙
You're gonna go to that bar. That guy. That guy right there.
站起來,去那裡,禮貌地問那個人 能否讓你口交
Get up, go over there, and politely ask that man can you suck his dick.
哦,上帝,真不敢相信我要做這個
Oh, my gosh. I can't believe I'm about to do this.
生存
Survival.
為了活下來
Go survive.
好吧,我只能上了
All right. I'll just go do it.
是的,上吧
Yes, go do it.
好吧
JAMES: Okay.
上啊,我們還做不做?
MAN: Come on. Are we doing this or not, okay?
是,我們肯定要做
JAMES: Yes, we're definitely doing it.
嘿,我第一次唱卡拉OK也緊張 對嗎?
Hey, I was nervous the first time I did karaoke, right?
站起來,上去唱
Just get up there and sing.
這是什麼爛前戲啊,趕緊吧
This is terrible foreplay. Come on.
- 我要把這個放進嘴裡 - 對
- I'm gonna put it in my mouth. - Yeah.
我要含你的...你的...
I'm gonna suck your di... Your di...
我要含你的...
I'm gonna suck your di...
我們來這就是為了這個
That's what we're here for.
我要把你的...放進嘴裡 我會給你...
I'll gonna put your di... in my mouth. I'm gonna give you he...
注意表情
Facial.
一飲而盡!
Down the hatch! Heh.
一個人吃飯?
Eating alone?
我只是想你也許需要個伴
I just thought you could use some company.
哦
Oh... Oh.
好吧,我明白了
Okay, I see what this is.
你認為你能跟我在一起?
You think that you can get with me?
- 哦,有趣的話題 - 等等,不,這不是請你坐下
- Interesting topic of conversation. - Wait. No. That wasn't a sit-down invitation.
- 你就像一個六 - 謝謝
- You're like a 6. - Thank you.
不,這不是誇獎你 你不是個好數字,我就像個九
No, it's not a compliment. That's not a good number. I'm like a 9.
如果我要加入這個遊戲...
If I were to get into this game...
你知道的,基佬遊戲...
- You know, the gay game... - Uh-huh.
順便一提,玩基佬遊戲,你會是贏家
By the way, the gay game is a game you can win.
不,不會,因為我根本不想玩 我說的是“如果”
No, it's not, because I don't wanna play. I'm saying "if."
如果你決定加入,那邊替補席上 有個位置
There's a spot on the bench for you, if you decide to join.
不,我不是替補,老兄
No, I'm not on the bench, man.
好吧,首發陣容!
Okay, starter! Heh.
我不是同性戀,老兄
I'm not gay, man.
我來這兒是陪一個朋友 他要做些基佬的事
I'm here, supporting a friend, doing some gay stuff.
很抱歉,我的名字是克里斯 我還真是艷福不淺啊
I'm sorry. My name is Chris. It's short for Christmas Came Early This Year.
老兄,你在哪兒?
Where are you at, man?
快點,老兄
MAN: Come on, man.
放長線釣大魚
This is gonna help me in the long run.
- 這裡,就是那裡 - 別用這個指著我
- Here. Right there. - Don't point it at me.
嘿!玩得開心點,好嗎?
Hey! Have fun with it, right?
- 玩得開心點 - 好
- Have fun with it. - Yeah.
- 加油 三、二、一!含進嘴裡!
- Come on. - Three, two, one! In the mouth!
聽著,老兄,你會找到意中人的
Look, you're gonna find you someone, man.
你只是要把眼光放得實際些,懂嗎?
You just gotta set your sights on something more realistic, you know?
你得放長遠點,想想長遠關係
You gotta think long-term. Think about the relationship.
你想跟誰一起撫養那個中國寶寶?
Who are you gonna raise that Chinese baby with?
不知道
- I don't know. - Hm?
你想跟誰一起奪回清風房車?
Who are you gonna restore that Airstream camper with?
你想跟誰去新罕布什爾吃床上早餐?
Who are you gonna drive and open that bed-and-breakfast in New Hampshire with?
- 這是我需要聽的 - 是的!是
- This is what I need to hear. - Yes! Yes.
我做不到,我試了,就是不行! 你必須訓練我
I can't do it. I really tried. I just can't! You have to train me.
這是我最後的機會
It's my last chance.
你準備好接受 比以前更加嚴酷的訓練了嗎?
You ready to train harder than you've ever trained?
因為我們一旦開始,就不可能停止
Because once we go, we do not hold back.
我們要做!要努力做!
We do it! And we do it hard!
準備好雄起了嗎?!
Are you ready to get hard?
準備好了,我準備好雄起了!
I am ready. I'm ready to get hard!
- 你要證明給我看你可以雄起! - 我會證明給你!
- You're gonna show me you can get hard! - I'm gonna show you!
我會拼命去雄起! 我會證明給你我有多厲害!
I'm gonna get so hard! Because I'm gonna show you how hard!
這正是我想聽到的 現在回家,拼命雄起
That's what I wanna hear. Then let's go home and get hard.
我想要擁有他們那種感情
I want what they have.
耶!
Yeah!
好啊,詹姆斯!
Yeah, James!
耶!
Yeah!
第二條準則:保護地盤
耶!
- - Unh! - DARNELL: Yeah!
這就是我要說的!
That's what I'm talking about!
夠了!
- Ugh. - Sho' enough!
恐懼口交會給予一個人力量
Fear of dick-sucking will give a man strength.
僅限員工
混蛋
Fuck you.
去你媽的!
Fuck cock!
該死!
Shit!
嘿,後退!你最好讓這些乳頭 離我的臉遠點!否則我讓你好看!
Hey, back off! You better get those tits out of my face! Or I'll show you my tits!
- 你在幹嘛? - 練習說髒話
- What are you doing? - Working on my trash talk.
讓其他獄友尊重你
You know, to get respect from the other inmates.
說給我聽聽
Let me hear some of it.
好吧
All right. Ahem.
嘿,朋友,我要踢破你的屁股
Hey, pal. I'm about to tear you a new ass.
詹姆斯,你得表現得更凶狠一點
You gonna have to do a little better than that, James.
嘿,我要踢破你的屁股
Hey, I'm about to tear you a new ass.
把你的屁股縫起來!
And sew up your old ass!
好的,就是這樣
Okay. All right.
我要揍扁你!
I'm gonna punch you in the fuck!
我要把你變成婊子中的婊子!
I'm gonna make you my bitch's bitch!
你就會成為大婊子!
You're gonna be my grand-bitch!
對,你的乾炮圈 馬上就能得到二十個點贊
Yeah. You're about to 20 likes on Instafuck.
如果再叫我在這裡看見你 我就在你屁股上蓋個戳
If I see you around here again, I'm gonna put a hashtag on your ass.
看看要打多少下才能蓋上
And see how many hits it gets.
哦,我的上帝
- Hmm? - Oh, my God.
希望你帶了好又多的會員卡 因為你要買一大堆陰莖棒!
Hope you brought your Costco card, because you're about to get dick in bulk!
什麼?太不幸了
What? This is so dark.
吃五道帶雞巴的菜如何?
How does a prix fixe dinner of five courses of dick sound?
- 你吃有機食品? - 什麼?
- You eat organic? - What?
一份新鮮的、熱烘烘的睪丸怎麼樣!
How about fresh farm-to-table, a purée of my balls!
耶,陰莖節快樂,聖雞雞!
Yeah. Merry Dickmas, Santa Cock! Hmm?
好了,好吧,老兄
Okay. All right, man.
詹姆斯,這些話都是哪來的?
Where is this stuff coming from, James?
嘿,小子,你讓你的父母失望了
Hey, son. You're a disappointment to your parents.
他倆我都幹過!
Who I fucked!
哦,該死
Oh, shit.
詹姆斯,這不正常 想想這個你就會發瘋
James, this is sick. You gotta be crazy to think of this.
這樣發瘋是好的
That crazy is good.
謝謝,我還有六個小時的髒話在這裡
Thank you. I've got about six hours more.
好,詹姆斯,很好
That's good, James. That's really good.
我喜歡這個,很喜歡
I like that. I like that a lot.
我希望你帶著你的陰莖打孔卡 因為第八個是免費的
I hope you brought your dick punch-card because the eighth dick is free.
刺!
Stab!
啊,該死!好了
Shit! Okay.
詹姆斯,乾得不錯
That's not bad, James.
乾得非常棒
That's not bad at all.
有進步
Progress.
彼得吹簫手挑了許多醃制的雞雞!
Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled cocks!
不錯
Yes.
入獄前十天
嘿、嘿、嘿! 準備好開始今天的工作了嗎?
Hey, hey, hey! You ready to get to work today?
- 你好 - 這都是什麼玩意?
- Hello. - What's all this stuff?
哦,這些是刀子
Oh, these are shanks.
或者說“刀”
Or "shivs."
在蘇格蘭,人們稱其為“利器”
In Scotland, they're referred to as "chibs."
實際上,這個是我做給你的
In fact, I made this one for you.
- 給我的? - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
我只想說,謝謝你所做的一切
Just to say thank you for all the hard work.
啊,老兄
Oh, man.
兄弟會 這很好,很酷
That's nice. That's cool.
哇哦,哇哦,別握著刀刃 你以前沒拿過刀嗎?握這裡
Whoa, whoa. Don't hold it by the blade. Haven't you ever held one before? Right here.
是的,我沒拿過 我的室友以前總拿著刀
Yeah, no, my cellie used to hold them all the time.
我不喜歡刀,刀引起太多糾紛
I don't like them. They cause too much trouble.
你在操場亮出刀,會招來攻擊 他們會這麼做的
You pull that out on the yard, somebody come out attack you, they can do this to you.
現在你要怎麼做? 你懂我的意思嗎?
Now what do you do? You know what I mean?
見鬼的,這從哪來的?
What the hell? Where'd that come from?
我自學的屁股保護方法
I taught myself how to keister.
屁股保護方法?在屁股上?
How to keister? Up the keister?
看,這是電動牙刷的一部分 很有效
Look, the electronic toothbrush part, it still works.
哦,不,好了,詹姆斯,關掉它
Oh, no. Okay, James. Cut it off.
關掉它,老兄,拿開
Cut it off. Get it out of my face, man.
我不用手就能啟動它
I can turn it on with no hands.
我不想看這個 我不想看這個戲法
I don't want to see that. I don't want to see that trick.
好了,放回去,上帝啊
It's okay. Put it back. God.
- 放回去? - 不,不,不
- Put it back? - No. No, no.
停,停,停,拜託停下
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop. Please.
- 想我教你怎麼做嗎? - 不,我想跳過這個
- Do you want me to teach you how? - No, I'm gonna pass on that.
首先,呼氣
It starts with a simple inverse inhale.
詹姆斯,停下
James, stop it.
同時放鬆括約肌
That, with a simultaneous relaxing of the sphincter.
我不想知道
I don't wanna know.
你確定?
You sure?
我確定,我只想問你個問題
I'm positive. I just wanna ask you one question.
我在那裡,摸著所有那些刀柄
I was over there, and I was touching all those shanks.
它們...?
Were they, uh...?
- 能放進後面? - 是,能放進去嗎?
- Keistered? - Yeah. Were they keistered?
大部分,是的
Most of them. Yeah.
入獄前八天
我們要模擬一場監獄暴亂
We're about to simulate a prison riot.
你要明白那是監獄裡最危險的時候
Understand that this is the most dangerous situation there is.
囚犯害怕,獄警也害怕
Prisoners are scared. Guards are scared.
活下來的關鍵是克服恐懼
The key to surviving is to not freak out.
- 我的上帝,暴亂時會發生什麼? - 傑傑裡奧會向你扔些東西
- Good Lord. What's gonna happen? - Cecelio's just gonna throw some stuff at you.
一些自負的人,一些骯髒的 無家可歸的傢伙,他能拿到的一切
Some roosters, some mangly homeless guys, whatever he's got.
- 這讓他興奮十足 - 好的,來吧
- He's really excited about this. - Okay. Let's do it.
等等,沒有防彈衣嗎?
Wait, don't I get body armor?
不,我們沒那個美國時間 傑傑裡奧!
No. We don't have that type of time. Cecelio!
為什麼沒有足夠時間?
Why don't we have enough time?
記住,別害怕
Remember, do not freak out.
燈光!
Lights!
音樂!
Music!
誰想參加派對?!
Who wants to party?!
上啊!上啊!上啊!
Go! Go! Go!
傑傑裡奧!把雞放進去!
DARNELL: Cecelio! Release the chickens!
不、不、不,詹姆斯!別害怕!
No, no, no, James! Don't freak out!
達尼爾,那有隻狒狒!
JAMES: Darnell, there's a baboon!
你現在在我的地盤!
- DARNELL: You're in my world now! - Aah!
來人,放我出去!
Someone let me out!
振作起來,別害怕!
DARNELL: Stop freaking out!
漂亮!
It's fucking beautiful!
哦,見鬼!
Oh, shit!
去死!去死!
Die! Die!
傑傑裡奧,關掉它!
DARNELL: Cecelio, turn it off!
關掉它!
Turn it off!
詹姆斯,我失控了!
James, I've lost control!
傑傑裡奧!退回去!我失去控制了!
Cecelio! Pull back! I have lost control!
哦,我的上帝!
Oh, my God!
- 啊,上帝! - 哦,我的上帝
- - God! - JAMES: Oh, my God.
見鬼!
Shit!
- 我被刺了! - 不!
- JAMES: I'm stabbed! - No!
- 我被刀割了! - 不,老兄,你割傷了我!
- JAMES: I'm cut! - No, you cut me, man!
你刺傷了我!
You stabbed me!
- 不,我沒有! - 不,你有!
- No, I didn't! - Yes, you did!
我告訴你別害怕 你卻嚇呆了!上帝!等等!
I told you, don't freak out! You freaked out! God! Wait...
- 不,我很好 - 等一下
- JAMES: No, I'm okay. - Hold up.
那只是紅酒而已
JAMES: It's just the wine.
老兄,我看到酒精對你有什麼作用
I see all the wine, man.
我感覺很好
I totally feel fine.
- 哦,見鬼! - 什麼?那是...
- Oh, fuck! - What? It's a...
- 另一把原來在這裡 - 好了,坐下來
- Oh, that's where the other one went. - Okay, just sit down.
- 這是一把刀,只是一把刀 - 是,我知道
- It's a shiv. It's just a shiv. - Yes, I know.
嘿,別嚇壞了
Hey, don't freak out.
- 我要把刀拔出來 - 好的
- I'm gonna pull it. - Okay.
DARNELL GRUNTS THEN JAMES SCREAMING
哦,我的老天
Oh, my God.
這玩意就像魚鉤 你越往外拉,它越往裡鑽
It's like a fishhook. The more you pull, the deeper it lodges.
好了,好了,聽著,我老婆是護士 我把你帶到她那去,好嗎?
All right. Okay. Look, my wife's a nurse. Let's get you to my wife. Okay?
上帝,哦,上帝
God. Oh, God.
哦,上帝,哦,我的上帝
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
它要從我頭裡戳出來了
It's sticking right out of my head.
聽著,詹姆斯,我不想再看了 我要開始...
James, listen. I don't want to look at it no more because I'm starting to...
哦,該死,我太害怕了
Oh, shit. I'm so scared.
我知道,見鬼的你能不能把頭...
I know. Can you fucking just keep your head...
- 哦,上帝! - 你弄得更深了
- Oh, God! - You drove it in a little deeper.
哦,上帝,詹姆斯,對不起...
Oh, God. Oh, James, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 我的眼睛在抽搐嗎? - 沒有!
- Is my eye twitching? - No!
- 回答我,我的眼睛在抽搐嗎? - 你的眼睛看起來很好
- Answer the question. Is my eye twitching? - It look fine.
- 真的?看起來很好? - 是的,很好,老兄,沒什麼問題
- Yeah? Does it look fine? - Yeah, fine, man. There's nothing wrong.
- 那玩個記憶遊戲,好嗎?準備 - 好了
- Let's play a memory game, okay? Engage. - Yes.
- 告訴我十二個月份 - 月份
- Give me 12 months. - Months.
一、二...
One, two...
- 不 - 四...
- No. - Four...
夏天,聖誕節...
Summer, Christmas...
- 什麼? - 烤土豆...
- What? - Baked potato...
- 什麼“烤土豆”? - 等等,我是不是少說了一個月?
- What is "baked potato"? - Wait. Did I leave one out?
不,你是對的,你是對的 這些是月份
No. You're right. You're right. Those are the months.
爸爸,謝謝你開車送我來學校
Thanks for driving me to college, Dad.
什麼?搞什麼?
What? What the fuck?
但是別在你把我送到宿舍時哭 不然我也該哭了
But don't start crying when you drop me off at the dorm, because then I'll start crying.
我愛你,爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也愛你,夥計
Love you too, man.
- 我該下車了 - 詹姆斯!不!不!
- This is where I need to get out. - James! No! No!
關門!關門!
Close the door! Close the door!
- 我們在柯契拉? - 不,詹姆斯!
- Are we at Coachella? - No, James!
麗塔,再次感謝你 把我頭上的刀子取下來
Rita, thank you once again for taking the knife out of my head.
瑪凱拉,怎麼...?
RITA: Makayla, what...?
小妞
Young lady.
但他正在做
But he's doing it.
這很美味
This is delicious.
好了,詹姆斯,詹姆斯
- DARNELL: Okay, James. James. - Grr.
停,停,你不必像這樣吃東西 你在休假
Stop. Stop. You don't have to eat like that. You're on furlough.
抱歉,這是我訓練的一部分
Sorry. It's part of my training.
如果你任由別人找你麻煩,不讓你 好好吃飯,你就是一個廢物
If you let someone mess with your food, you're a punk.
儘管這很美味
It's delicious, though.
聽著,你需要立刻打住
Look, you need to shut this stuff down right now.
你不知道你的所作所為會在 他入獄前就害死他嗎?
Do you understand you're gonna get him killed before he even gets to prison?
- 你在說什麼? - 達尼爾表現很棒
- What are you talking about? - Darnell's doing a wonderful job.
- 他是個好老師 - 看到了?
- He's a great teacher. - See that?
也是一個很好的朋友
And a great friend.
我唯一搞不懂的就是 他怎麼會進監獄的
I just can't figure out how he ever went to jail in the first place.
老天,我也不知道
RITA: Gosh, me neither.
達尼爾,怎麼不告訴詹姆斯 你過去是怎麼走上歧途的?
Darnell, have you every shared with James the story of how you went away?
不,他沒有
No, he hasn't.
嗯,他現在還沒準備好告訴你這些
Well, he's not really ready for that right now.
瑪凱拉在這裡呢
And I got Makayla at the table.
我是說,她是一個已判刑的重罪犯的 女兒,她很堅強
I mean, she's the daughter of a convicted felon. She's strong.
- 嗯 - 說得好
- Mm-hm. - JAMES: Good point.
你為什麼不講講?別省略任何細節
Why don't you tell it? Don't leave out details.
我很想聽聽 我認為會對我有幫助
I'd love to hear it. I think it could really help me.
好吧
Okay, uh...
我們就是在街邊的混混
We was just some boys in the hood.
我,我的好友,裡基和步兵
Me, my man, Ricky, and Doughboy.
步兵的真名是羅素 我們關係很好,夥計
Doughboy's real name was Russell. We was close, man.
說到裡基,裡基很特別 因為他前途光明
Thing about Ricky, Ricky was special, because Ricky had the ticket.
裡基是名出色的橄欖球四分衛 他有望直升大學
Ricky was star quarterback. You know, he had a college future.
他是我們的黃金男孩,你明白嗎?
He was our golden boy, you know?
我們和一些傢伙起了糾紛 你知道,幫派群毆什麼的
We got into it with some other guys. You know, some gangbang stuff.
在回家的路上我們分開了
Uh, on the way home we decide to split up.
我和步兵說我們走這邊
Me and Doughboy said we'll go this way.
裡基說他走那邊
Ricky said he'll go this way.
我和步兵轉回來,發現裡基躺在地上
Me and Doughboy come around, we see Ricky on the ground.
裡基中槍了
Ricky got shot.
我跑到那裡,我跑啊,跑啊
I run over there. I'm running, I'm running.
我抓起他,把他的頭抱在懷裡 我看著他,哭喊,“裡基!
I grab him. I got his head on my arm. I'm looking. I'm like, "Ricky!"
裡基!
Ricky!"
裡基”
"Ricky."
他本前途光明啊!
He had the ticket!
他們殺了他
They got him.
步兵說,“來吧,兄弟,站起來 讓他去吧,他已經死了”
Doughboy's like, "Come on, man. Get up. Let him be. He's done."
我站起來
I get up.
步兵說,“你知道這是什麼意思 意思是我們要挺身而出”
Doughboy says, "You know what this mean. This mean we gotta step up."
我說,“你說得對,就是這樣” 所以我們武了個裝
I said, "You damn right, it does." So we strapped up.
- 我不知道那是什麼意思 - 我們弄到了噴子
- I don't know what that means. - It means we got the burners.
我不知道那是什麼意思
I don't know what that means.
我們弄到了槍
It means we went and got the guns.
那晚我們發現了那些傢伙
We saw those guys later that night.
三槍爆頭
Three headshots. Pop! Pop! Pop!
- “這是為了裡基!” - 毫無疑問
- "That's for Ricky!" - For sure.
警察來了,夥計
Cops came, man.
我告訴步兵我來擔下一切
I told Doughboy I'd take the rap.
我說,“你快走,繼續過你的生活 我會告訴他們一切都是我做的”
I said, "You go ahead. Live your life. I'll tell them it was me."
警察來了,我說,“是我做的”
Cops came. I said, "I did it."
我進了監獄
I went to jail.
你為羅素犧牲了你的自由和人生
You gave your life and your freedom for Russell.
忠誠如一
Loyal to a fault.
事情就是這樣
It is what it is.
就是我如今還在洗車的原因
That's why I wash cars today.
因為我的雙手沾滿鮮血
Because I got blood on my hands.
就像麥克白夫人一樣
Just like Lady MacBeth.
像麥克白
- - Huh? - JAMES: Like MacBeth.
是的
Yes.
- Yes. - Phew.
哇,真是個好故事
Wow, what a story.
聽起來簡直就像一部電影
Almost sounds like a movie.
對啊
RITA: Phew. Yeah.
達尼爾,你怎麼不告訴他 那時一位白人女士來了,收養了你...
Darnell, why don't you tell him about that time that that white lady came and adopted you...
為你申訴改判為防衛過當
and turned you into an offensive tackle.
我想今晚我們說的夠多了
I think we've talked enough tonight.
我叫的車來了
Oh. There's my cab.
我得在關門前趕回去 要不傑傑裡奧會活埋了我
I'd better get back before lockdown or Cecelio will put me in the hole.
他喜歡教訓我
He loves putting me in the hole.
- 我送你出去,老兄 - 不必麻煩了
- Well, let me walk you out, man. - No, that's fine.
感謝你所做的一切
Thanks for everything.
詹姆斯,很高興見到你
James, it was wonderful meeting you.
我也很高興遇見你
JAMES: Great to meet you too.
你知道,長大後,我的家人 從未像這樣聚在一起
You know, growing up, my family would never spend any time together like this.
你們很幸運
You guys are very lucky.
- 再見,瑪凱拉 - 再見,金先生
- Bye, Makayla. - Bye, Mr. King.
再見
Bye-bye.
嘿,你爸爸從沒進過監獄,好嗎?
Hey, your dad never went to jail, okay?
我看過《街區男孩》
I've seen Boyz n the Hood.
誰給你看的《街區男孩》?
Who showed you Boyz n the Hood?
爸爸,我不認為是他做的
Daddy, I don't think he did it.
他當然沒有
Of course he didn't.
你要做些真正能幫助到他的事
You need to do something that's really gonna help him.
他在監獄裡撐不了多久
He will not last in prison.
他甚至在我的學校裡都撐不下去
He wouldn't even last in my school.
你好,我是詹姆斯
Hello, this is James.
嘿,是我,達尼爾 聽著,老兄,我想了想
Hey. It's me, Darnell. Look, man, I've been thinking it over...
我覺得在你入獄時 給你找些額外的保護是個好主意
and it might be a good idea to get you extra protection on the inside.
所以明天我們要去我的表兄弟羅素家 現在聽我說,詹姆斯
So tomorrow we're gonna go over to my cousin Russell's house. Now listen.
我的表兄弟羅素和他的夥伴 是與我們完全不同的人
DARNELL: Russell and his friends, they're different dudes.
對外來者很有戒心
Very suspicious of outsiders.
我是說,當你走進那裡 他們很可能立刻認為你是警察
You walking in there, they're probably gonna think you a cop off the bat.
所以為了避免遇到危險 我需要你做些事情
So I need you to do something for me so we don't create any dangerous situations.
- 穿得更隨便些 - 把臉涂黑
- DARNELL: Dress casually. - Blackface.
這是搞什麼啊?!
What the fuck was that?!
- 明天見 - 詹姆斯,詹姆斯
- See you tomorrow. - DARNELL: James. - James.
詹姆斯,別做蠢事,穿得隨便些
James, don't do nothing stupid. Just dress casual.
入獄前七天
HORN HONKING
- 行頭不錯啊 - 該死的你在幹什麼?
- Nice whip. - What the hell are you doing?
- 你覺得你打扮得像誰,詹姆斯? - 李爾·韋恩
- Who you supposed to be dressed like, James? - Little Wayne.
- 他上一次現場秀就是這麼穿的 - 哦,李爾·韋恩
- It's what he wore at his last runway show. - Oh, Lil Wayne.
你告訴我需要入鄉隨俗,所以我 熬了一整夜,研究你們的文化
You told me I needed to try to fit in, so I stayed up all last night studying your culture.
- 抱歉,你說什麼? - 對於那些說爵士樂
- I'm sorry, what? - And to those who say jazz...
是唯一美國本土的藝術形式 我要說,我的朋友,聽聽傑斯的歌
is the only indigenous American art form, I say listen to a little Jay-Z, my friend.
我忘了杜松子酒和果汁 我是否該回家去拿呢?
I forgot the gin and juice. Should I run back inside?
你能別晃了嗎?
Will you stop?
我不會盜用你們的文化
I'm not trying to appropriate your culture.
- 這很棒,我會告訴其他人 - 我只想說
- That's great. I'll tell the others. - I'm just saying...
嘻哈是一種非常 複雜多面的亞文化...
hip-hop is a very sophisticated, multifaceted subculture...
適合所有類型的人群
that speaks to all different types of people.
那音樂,風尚,態度,力量...
The music, the fashions, the attitudes, the beefs...
我讀得越多,聽得越多...
The more I read, the more I listened...
越能接觸到其豐富的文化內涵
the more I felt connected to its rich cultural tapestry.
那真是太好啦,現在,拜託我們 可以結束這番對話了嗎?
That is really great. Now, can we please be done with this conversation?
別再晃了
Please stop.
我想我知道是誰殺了圖帕克
I think I know who killed Tupac.
- 下一個! - 搞什麼鬼?
- JAMES: I got next! - What the fuck?
- 你好 - 我要給你屁股加個蓋
- Hello. - MAN: I'm gonna put a cap in yo ass.
你他媽是誰?!
Who the fuck are you?!
- 他沒問題,他是跟我來的 - 那你他媽是誰,黑鬼?
- Yo, he's good. He with me. - And who the fuck are you, nigga?
嘿,羅素,羅素!
Hey, Russell. Russell!
羅素
Russell.
羅素!是我
Russell! Excuse me.
你好,詹姆斯·金,高級基金經理 威爾索普基金管理
JAMES: Hello. James King, Senior Fund Manager, Wealthrop Funds.
- 詹姆斯,快走吧 - 對不起,過一下
- James, come on. - JAMES: Excuse me. Right through here.
他就是你說的那位 你要幫他做好準備進監獄的王八蛋?
Hell no, man. Is this the motherfucker who you said you had to get ready for prison, man?
我需要保護,我希望能加入 克倫肖王一夥
Well, I need protection, and I'm hoping to join the Crenshaw Kings.
是嗎?
Are you? Ha-ha-ha.
嘿,我過去見過白人,我的緩刑監督官 就是白人,你明白我的意思嗎?
I've seen white people before. My probation officer is white. You know what I'm saying?
但是你,混賬 你白得像蛋黃醬,老兄
But you, motherfucker, man, you white as mayonnaise, man. Ha-ha-ha.
見鬼,也許是黑臉的蛋黃醬 誰知道呢?
Oh, shit. Maybe in blackface. Who knows? Ha-ha-ha.
嘿,聽著,我來告訴你
Hey, listen. I tell you what though.
老兄,你穿得倒是很對
You damn sure got your get-up right, man.
我是說,迷彩和豹紋 這是明確寫在幫派手冊上的
I mean, camouflage and cheetah print, that's straight out the gangbanger's handbook.
對,就像李爾·韋恩,對嗎?
Yeah, yeah, like Lil Wayne, right?
正是,謝謝你
Exactly. Thank you.
我喜歡這個
MOUTHS I love it.
聽著,他沒打算加入我們,好嗎?
Look, he's not trying to be a member, okay?
他只想你能在他入獄期間保護他
He just wants you to protect him while he's on the inside.
就像達尼爾擔下罪名時你為他做的
Like you did for Darnell when he took the rap for you.
什麼?
What?
這件事我們下次再談
We can talk about that another time.
- 好 - 不
- Yeah. - No.
所以繼續說下去
So let's let that go.
你記得,你知道
You remember. You know.
記得裡基所做的,他的光明前途...
With what Ricky did and the ticket...
你嚇壞了,達尼爾控制了場面 擔下了一切
and you freaked out and Darnell took control of the situation.
- 停 - 這他媽...?
- Stop. - Is this motherfucking...?
《街區男孩》,老兄
Boyz n the Hood, man.
- 這真不是時候 - 好吧,我告訴你,老兄
- - This is a bad time. - RUSSELL: Okay, I tell you what, man.
我告訴你:
I tell you what:
來談談吧
Humor me.
我是個公平的人
I'm a fair person.
我是個商人
And I'm a businessman.
完全的專業人士
Clear professional.
你的生活有什麼價值?
What's your life worth to you?
一百萬美元聽上去怎樣?
- How does a million dollars sound? - Ha-ha-ha.
“一百萬美元聽上去怎樣?”
"How does a million dollars sound?" Ha-ha-ha.
大家注意,都退後 交給我來處理
Hold up, everybody. Stand back. I'll handle it.
一百萬美元聽上去怎樣?
How does a million dollars sound?
兄弟,一百萬美元聽上去 就像是個帶六個零數字
Million dollars sound like a one with six zeros behind it with two commas separating them.
然而,大家都從有線電視新聞網上聽到 以及從華爾街日報上看到...
However, from the sound of CNN and the looks of The Wall Street Journal...
只要耳不聾眼不瞎的人都得知了 你破產的消息,該死
and everybody else with eyes and ears go to get they news, you broke, motherfucker.
你的資產已經被凍結了 並且不會那麼快有機會被解凍
Your assets have been frozen with no chances of thawing anytime soon.
所以你也就是...
So you probably got as much or less...
比你身邊的那位不怎麼樣 還喜歡玩心眼兒的廢物...
than this little no-good, manipulative, degenerate motherfucker...
強一點
right here next to you.
我不得不問一下 “你懂我在說什麼嗎?”
Which forces me to ask the question, "Are you fucking with me?"
你覺得這是他媽的兒戲嗎? 你覺得我在搞笑嗎?
You think this a motherfucking game? You think I'm playing?
你為什麼出現在我的地盤,我的房子裡
Why would you come up in my hood, in my house...
假裝自己很有料 還承諾完全兌現不了的事?
and present yourself as something you not, offering shit you can't deliver?
- 這個混賬讓你對我撒謊的嗎? - 羅素
- Did this motherfucker tell you to lie to me? - Russ.
該死的閉上你的嘴吧,夥計
Shut the fuck up, man.
我認為,你最好趕緊告訴我 你究竟能做什麼...
I think, real fast, you need to tell me what the fuck you gonna do...
才能說服我留著你的小命
to make me wanna keep motherfuckers off your ass.
你可是在跟詹姆斯·金說話
You're talking to James King.
讓我為你創造財富吧
Let me create wealth for you.
所以通常最少買進 五百萬奈克斯爾基金
So the normal minimum buy-in to the Nexel Fund is 5 million...
但我可以讓你們這些傢伙 用經紀商賬戶
but I can get you guys in using a brokerage pocket account.
換句話說,那兩個磚頭大小的可卡因 然後把它放在這兒
In other words, liquidate two bricks of cocaine and park it right here.
現在隨著基金以往的業績表現 它將會在每三到五年翻一倍
With the historical performance of the fund, that's gonna double every three to five years...
然後我們可以毫不費力地獲得 一百二十萬美元
and we're looking at, mm, $1.2 million easy.
除了犯罪之外,才沒辦法賺那麼多錢
Ain't no way you're making that much money without committing a crime.
帶著對巴爾扎克的歉意
With apologies to Balzac.
你個混蛋,你在瞎扯淡什麼?
What the fuck? You talking about my ballsack?
不,我們將要做的是,獲得...
No. What we're gonna do is we get other people's money...
那些在市場上做出 相反預測的人的錢
who've made an opposite prediction on the market.
好,我會卷起他們的錢,然後全部帶走
Okay, we gonna roll on them and take they money.
那些窩囊廢有錢玩這麼大嗎?
Just how strapped are these loser motherfuckers?
噢,我可不擔心
Oh, I wouldn't worry.
我已經從他們那裡拿了好幾百萬了
I've taken millions from them...
他們還沒有騎到我頭上來
and they haven't stepped to me yet.
那些窩囊廢
Loser motherfuckers.
該死的,蛋黃醬來勢洶洶哦
Damn. Mayo is badass.
股市就是個黑幫 拿走你的錢讓別人沒得拿,對嗎?
Stock market is gangster. Take what's yours and fuck the other guy, right?
華爾街的精英們,兄弟 那些才是真正的罪犯
Wall Street, man. Those are the real criminals.
那些傢伙殺完人還逍遙法外
Those guys get away with murder.
等等,兄弟 你一直在殺人,老黑
Wait, man. You murder people all the time, Black.
對,沒錯,殺人是我的最愛
Oh, yeah. Murder's my favorite.
他們在想:拜託,別殺我
And they think, "Oh, please, don't kill me."
我喜歡,就好像說:我不會殺你的
I love it. And I'm like, "I'm not gonna kill you."
他們放鬆,然後說:馬上趴在地上!
They relax, then I'm like, "Boom, get on the ground now!
趴下,趴下!
Get on the ground! Get on the ground!"
我要殺了你!我要殺了你!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
- 我殺人上癮了 - 別擔心
- I get excited about murder. - Don't worry about it.
我在笑
I'm... I'm laughing.
你這次做得還湊合
You should know, you did all right this time.
你的兄弟蛋黃醬是個賺錢機器
Your boy, Mayo, is an earner.
你會不會給他一些 內部的幫助?
Are you gonna get him some help on the inside?
我會幫他的
I'll help him.
但不是我們 你知道的,內部都是有色人種
But not with us. You know, inside it's all about color.
那傢伙需要加入一個白人黑幫
Dude need a white gang.
非常純粹的白人黑幫
A very white gang.
但我會找找關係幫他一把
But I'll put the play together.
進監獄六天前
白人聯盟
我一定要加入這個黑幫嗎?
JAMES: That's the gang I have to join?
他們好像有點種族歧視
They seem kind of racist.
不是有點,他們完全就是
Ain't no "kind of." They are.
那是白人聯盟會
That's the Alliance of Whites.
那也是你唯一 能在監獄中生存下去的機會
That's also your only chance of survival in prison...
所以你需要融入他們,並且需要 讓他們確信你是他們中的一員
so you need to go in there and you need to make them believe that you're one of them.
可事實上,他們叫我黑鬼 你也說來聽聽吧,自然一點
Matter of fact, call me the N-word. But say it like you mean it, though. Let me hear it.
什麼?不可能
What? No.
趕緊說吧,快點,詹姆斯,我現在 准許你說這個詞
That's the wrong N-word. Come on, James, I'm giving you a free pass right now.
在這輛車裡,黑鬼這個詞完全沒問題 不就是個詞嘛,來吧
In this truck, the N-word is perfectly fine. Just another word right now. Go ahead.
可那感覺還是不太...
That still doesn't feel...
好吧,讓我們試試這個 白的反義詞是什麼?
Let's try this. What's that place where your leg bends?
黑?
My knee?
沒錯,那麼 跑火車的叫鐵什麼?
Okay. And, uh, what noise does a-angry dog make?
- 軌? - 現在,把它們放在一起講
- Grr? - Put it together, though.
黑,黑...軌
Knee. Knee-grr.
該死!抱歉
- Ow! - Oh, shit! I'm sorry.
抱歉,兄弟,我情不自禁
I am sorry, man, that just happened.
沒控制住自己
That literally just happened.
哇哦,我給你揍得不輕
Wow, I got you good too.
不知不覺就打了
It just, like, jumped out, man.
就是個條件反射,真不知怎麼形容
It was a reflex. I really can't tell you.
我還沒說那個詞呢 我只是說了另外兩個詞
I didn't even say it. I was saying two other words.
抱歉,詹姆斯 你想讓我做什麼?
I apologize, James. What do you want me to do?
趕緊下車吧 到那邊努力表現一下
Just get your ass out the car and go in there, act hard.
融入他們,老兄,去吧
Fit in, man. Go ahead.
把燈關掉!該死!
Cut the light off! Shit!
耶!
Fuck yeah!
蜘蛛,該你了
MAN: Spider, you're up.
看著學,小子
Watch and learn, son.
嗨
Hi.
請各位聽我講下話 我只是在找那個叫蜘蛛的人
If I could have your attention, please. I'm just looking for Spider?
他是個緝毒警!
MAN: He's a narc!
聽著,你不能總依著他
Listen, this relationship can't just be built around him.
我的意思是,你也有權利做你開心的事 明白嗎?
You got a right to be happy too, you know?
是的,聽了你的一席話 我想通了
And I am, I am. And I think I'm open to it now because of our talk.
不錯,那太好了,很高興你聽進去了 很不錯
Yeah. That's good. I love the fact that you're listening. I love that.
你知道嗎,我交往過的男友 都沒有你這麼好
You know, you're the best boyfriend I never had.
好啦
Ha, ha. Okay. Ha-ha-ha.
好的,其實,我沒有完全放棄 還有時間
Yeah, well, I'm not totally giving up. There is time.
- 事情會隨著時間的流逝而改變的 - 不,不,它們不會的
- And things change with time. - No, no, they don't.
不,那永遠不會發生的
No. No, no. That's never gonna happen.
- 你只是現在這麼說 - 不,我永遠都會這麼說
- You say that now. - No, no, no. I'm always gonna say that.
好吧
- Okay. - Ha-ha-ha.
好的
Okay.
該死
Oh, shit.
嘿,我有點事,再聊嘍?
Hey, I gotta go, okay?
我晚點再跟你談,玩得開心
So I'll talk to you later. Have fun.
這裡是私人會所,猶太腦袋
Private club, Jew Hair.
講得漂亮,蜘蛛
Good one, Spider.
我就這麼走進來了
I walked right into that one. Heh.
詹姆斯·金,新教教徒
James King. Protestant.
肖克倫金的羅素 跟你們提到我了嗎?
But Russell, from the Crenshaw Kings, referred me?
是的,羅素說了你會來的
Yeah, Russell said you'd be by.
不管怎麼說,我將要進監獄了 我需要一些保護
Anyway, I'm going to prison and I need protection.
好吧,那你來對地方了,大個子
Well, welcome to the club, Jimbo.
太棒了!噢,上帝!
Great! Oh, good!
我們可以保護你 但是我們也有一些規則需要你來遵守
But you get protection from us, we got rules.
一些原則
Principles.
規則一
Rule number one:
當你加入之後,就不可以 跟黑人和拉丁裔人一起勾搭
When you're on the inside, you don't hang out with the niggers or the spics.
這個你能做到嗎,兄弟?
Now, do you have a problem with that, brother?
我嗎?
Me?
當然能
Of course not.
蜘蛛,你把我看成什麼人了?
Spider, what do you take me for?
我是個一流的種族主義者
I'm a big-time racist.
我超討厭黑
I hate the knee.
什麼?
What?
那是什麼玩意?
What is this shit?
我是說,我是一個典型的種族主義者 在我的棋子裡面,只有白棋
I mean, heck, I'm such a racist that my chess set, I only have white pieces.
這麼說有點讓人糊塗,但是我不會...
It's confusing, but I don't...
我不會給黑棋任何贏的機會
I won't give the blacks a chance to win.
該死
Oh, shit.
他是個該死的警察
He's a fucking cop.
- 他是個警察! - 我覺得不對勁
- MAN: He's a cop! - I smell bacon.
- 我不是警察 - 最討厭那些該死的緝毒警察了
- I'm not a cop. - Fucking hate narcs.
我們會追查出他究竟是幹什麼的
We'll find out what he is.
好的
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God.
該死的,天啊
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit. Oh, my God.
我只是想知道我適不適合 加入白人聯盟會而已
I'm just wondering if maybe I'm not the best fit for the Alliance of Whites.
在我撕破你的臉皮之前 你有什麼需要坦白的嗎?
You got anything to confess before I rip your face off?
好的!來啊!
JAMES: Fine! Go ahead!
殺了我吧!但是請告訴全世界我不是個賊!
Kill me! But please tell the world I'm not a thief!
我並沒有做那些他們所說的事
I did not do the things they said I did!
答應我,蜘蛛!答應我!
Promise me, Spider! Promise me!
燒死他
Burn him.
那是什麼鬼東西?!
MAN: The fuck was that?!
沒錯
That's right!
有個黑人帶著個噴火器進來了 你該知道這通常都會發生!
A black man just came in with a flamethrower, just like you always knew would happen!
是的!
Yeah!
惡魔降臨了,混蛋們!
The devil in here, bitch!
而且他還是個黑人
And he's a black man.
給我後退!退後!
Stay yo ass back! Stay back!
詹姆斯!我們走吧!
James! Let's go!
好的
Yeah.
- 你還好嗎? - 很好,快點吧
- You all right? - Yeah. Come on.
快點,快點吧,我們走吧
Come on. Come on, let's go.
知道麼?我想跟你們說點事兒
You know what? I got something I wanna say to y'all since I'm guessing...
我猜這是你們第一次 被強迫聽一個黑人的話
this is the first time that you've ever been forced to listen to a black man.
你知道嗎,可能你們這些傢伙 只需要冷靜點
You know, maybe you guys should just calm the fuck down.
黑人不會傷害你的!
Black people ain't trying to hurt you!
雖然我現在很有傷害力
I mean, technically, I am right now.
但那只是因為 你正在試圖對這位白人做的事
But that's only because of what you were trying to do to the white guy.
想想這些吧!
Think about that!
谷歌一下“我有一個夢想”,蠢貨們!
Google "I Have a Dream," assholes!
各位,這個時刻很有教育意義
It's a teachable moment here, people.
應該燒死這裡的每個人
Should burn everybody in here.
跑,詹姆斯!
Run, James!
噢,該死!把他們腦袋帶到我面前來!
- JAMES: Oh, shit! - Bring me their fucking heads!
跑,詹姆斯!快跑啊!
Run, James! Run!
你把那輛摩托車推倒有個屁用啊? 跑啊!
What the fuck are you knocking over the bike for?! Run!
噢,天啊,你就是講不出“黑鬼”啊?
Oh, God. You just couldn't say "nigger", huh?
什麼?你難道還不曉得 你生我氣是諷刺在哪裡嗎?
What?! You can't see the irony in being mad at me about that?
- 不! - 混賬東西!
- - No! - WOMAN: Motherfuckers!
- 那是納粹的乳房! - 而且它們非常巨大!
- It's Nazi titties! - And they're huge!
快跑!
Get out!
該死!
Oh, shit!
婊子,把你的白屁股移走!
- WOMAN: Whoa! - DARNELL: Bitch, get your white ass off!
見鬼!
Goddamn it! Ugh!
走吧,走吧,走吧!
JAMES: Oh, go, go, go!
- 你炸了我的俱樂部,猶太腦袋 - 該死!
- You blew up my club, Jew Hair! - Oh, shit!
後種族歧視的美國,混蛋!
JAMES: Post-racial America, assholes!
- 混蛋,納粹黨! - 耶!
- DARNELL: Fuck you, Nazis! - JAMES: Yeah!
我很高興能回到克倫肖 這裡很安全
JAMES: I'm so glad to be back in Crenshaw where it's safe.
我的一顆心現在終於落地了
My heart is just now finally settling.
是啊,我們還活著
Yeah. We're alive.
讓我們共同舉杯 來慶祝逃離該死的納粹主義吧
How about we make a toast to escaping fucking Nazis.
好
Yes. Heh.
你真的是無辜的,是嗎?
You really are innocent, aren't you?
的確是!
Yes.
- 當然 - 好的,詹姆斯,如果情況是這樣
- Absolutely. - Okay, so James, if that's the case...
那你為什麼不試著找陷害你的傢伙?
then why aren't you trying to find the guy that framed you?
我們在找
We are.
誰們在找?
Who are?
入獄四天前 馬丁有一調查小組 在夜以繼日調查此事
Now, Martin has a team of investigators working around the clock.
他時刻讓我知道最新進展,不過一大難題是:
He's keeping me up to date. But the million-dollar question is:
- 誰偽造了我的交易記錄? - 好,跟我說說
- Who falsified my transaction records? - All right, lay it on me.
好的,目前追蹤起來很複雜
All right. Now, this is very complicated to follow.
我不期望你首次就能明白 所以請仔細聽好了
I don't expect you to get it on the first pass, so listen very carefully.
在威爾索普基金管理上 你需要明白的一件事是...
The one thing you need to understand at the Wealthrop Fund...
一切都流經馬丁之手
is that everything flows through Martin.
- 明白嗎? - 明白
- Okay? - Okay.
所有與清算中心,交易者接觸的...
Any sort of contact with the clearing house, the traders...
接觸交易記錄和客戶信息...
access to trading records and client information...
國際賬戶,機構...
international accounts, institutions...
當然還有佣金的發放統統流經馬丁之手
and, of course, the doling out of commissions all goes through Martin.
- 所以是馬丁乾的 - 不會
- So it's Martin. - No.
你不是在開玩笑吧? 詹姆斯,這是常識
Are you fucking ki...? It's common sense, James.
聽著!所有箭頭都指向馬丁!
Look! All arrows point to Martin!
板子上唯一的名字就是馬丁!
The only name on the board is fucking Martin!
馬丁!馬丁!馬丁!
Martin! Martin! Martin!
拜託!詹姆斯,你需要專注
Come on! James, you need to focus.
你就要入獄了 除非你能證明是馬丁乾的
You're going to prison unless you can prove that Martin did it.
那麼我們需要獲得一手主記錄...
We'd need to get a hold of the master records...
也就是公司裡所有人的交易日誌
which is a log of all transactions made by anyone in the firm.
好,我們如何獲取?
- Okay, how do we get it? - Martin has the original copy...
馬丁把創立公司時的原件 存在了同一電腦上
on the same computer that he had when he started the company.
你是我見過的最蠢的天才 詹姆斯,起來!
You got to be the dumbest genius I've... Get up, James!
- 好的 - 去他的板子!詹姆斯,我們走!
- All right. - Fuck the board! Let's go, James!
我們去馬丁的辦公室
We're going to Martin's office.
詹姆斯,表現得自然點 你走起路來就像你有罪一樣
Act natural, James. You walking like you guilty.
- 嘿,老兄,你在看比賽? - 是的
- Hey, big guy, you catch the game? - Yeah.
嘿,老兄,我叫肯 我在這兒上班
Hey, big guy, my name is Ken. I work here.
它在這個櫃子裡
WHISPERING It's in this cabinet.
我們得想辦法把門打開
We just have to figure out a way to get the door open.
小心
Watch out.
搞定
I got it.
就是這個,他創立公司時的同一台電腦
Ugh. There it is. Same computer he had when he started the company.
幸運符
It's a good luck charm.
幸運符個屁
Good luck charm, my ass.
它與外邊世界沒有連接 沒電郵,沒互聯網,沒記錄
It has no connection to the outside world. No emails, no Internet, no trace.
在這裡,主記錄
JAMES: There it is. The master records.
這就是我們所需要的 這個讓我無罪開釋
That's what we need. This will clear my name.
好,那我們別浪費時間了 搬走吧
Well, then let's not waste time. Get it.
是的!我不會入獄了
Yes! I'm not going to prison.
更重要的是 我不會當任何人的替罪羊了
More importantly, I'm not gonna be anyone's bitch.
嘿,朋友,你美夢成真了
Hey, you are living the dream, my friend.
- 達內爾? - 什麼?
- Darnell? - Yeah?
聽著,你救了我的命
Look, you saved my life.
- 我不知道我以後怎麼報答你 - 哦,不用這樣
- I don't know how I'll ever repay you. - Oh, come on, man.
就這一次
Just this once.
好的,分開
MAN: All right, break it up.
把小推車留在那裡,躲開 快點躲開,快點,躲開
Leave the cart there and back away. Move away, come on. Move, move.
我尊重你的努力嘗試 但詹姆斯,夠了
I actually respect you for trying, but enough is enough, James.
好吧
All right.
你在做什麼?
What are you doing?
詹姆斯,你在做什麼呢?
James, what are you doing?
詹姆斯,別用瘋狗臉
DARNELL: Don't mad-dog, James.
他要朝我們開槍
He's gonna shoot us.
混蛋!
What the fuck?!
不,他要殺了我們
No. He's gonna kill us, man.
- 想乾架嗎?! - 哦,該死!
- Do you want some?! - Oh, fuck!
- 想挑戰我?! - 噢,上帝!
- Do you wanna step with me?! - God!
你最好...不要...
You'd better... Don't...
槍,抓住槍!
The gun! Grab the gun!
你為什麼不拿起槍!
- Huh? - Why don't you pick up the gun!
- 拿著! - 好,我拿到了,我拿到了!
- Grab it! - Yeah. I got it, I got it!
我拿到了,我拿到了
I got it. Yeah, I got it.
你看上去有點緊張,第一次握槍?
You look a little nervous. First time holding a gun?
不是
Nope.
狗娘養的,別動!
Motherfucker, freeze!
否則我崩了你!
Before I pop yo ass!
“崩我”?真的嗎?
"Pop"? Really?
我會聽他的 這個人是個危險的重罪犯
I would listen to him. This man's a dangerous felon.
是的,除了當我查他的記錄時 那是我見過的最乾淨的記錄
Yeah, except when I ran his record, it was the cleanest one I'd ever seen.
甚至連一張違章罰單都沒有
Not even a parking ticket.
- 沒錯 - 什麼?
- Yeah. - What?
你不知道?是的
You didn't know? Yeah.
別瞎鬧了,給我槍 快點,給我槍
Stop clicking around and give me the gun. Come on. Give me the gun.
我認為你把安全裝置打開了
I think you have the safety on.
可惡!
Shit! Ow.
看見了吧?安全裝置打開了
See? Safety's on.
安全裝置關閉
Safety off.
馬丁說的對,你是個幸運的傢伙
Martin was right. You are a lucky little shit.
不要再給我找到你的理由 你們都一樣
Don't give me reason to find you again. Either of you.
詹姆斯,不要對著我擺瘋狗臉
Don't you mad-dog me, James.
聽著,聽著,詹姆斯 我得解釋解釋!
Listen, listen, I got some explaining to do. James!
在我們抓住這個傢伙之後 我們可以談談這個
We can talk about this after we go catch this guy.
你這個叛徒!
You traitor!
- “叛徒”? - 你教給我的一切都是騙人的!
- "Traitor"? - Everything you taught me was a lie!
現在我倒霉透頂!
And now I'm fucked beyond all fucktitude!
我的人生倒霉透了!
My life's asshole is fucked!
別滿嘴噴髒話了!
You stop with your unorthodox style of cussing!
你只記住:
You just remember:
不管我在監獄裡發生什麼事情 全都是你的錯!
Whatever happens to me in there, it's your fault!
打住吧,一派胡言
Oh, stop. That's bullshit, man.
好吧,我可能在入獄這事上騙了你 但我做了該做的,我為你準備好了!
Okay, I may have lied to you about going to jail, but I did my job. I got you ready!
做好什麼準備?!
Ready for what?!
最扯的監獄?
Maximum-bullshit prison?
因為你,我差點給別人吹了簫!
I almost sucked a dick because of you!
我才不在乎
I don't even give a shit.
這是我的招牌
It's my sign.
入獄前兩天
愛爾蘭共和軍的好處就是 如果你想要錢去上學或者買房子
Now, the great thing about an IRA, if you need the money for education or a first home...
那幫混蛋就撤回懲罰
motherfuckers can make withdrawal penalty-free.
說實話,我分不清 羅斯和傳統個人退休賬戶
I honestly don't get the difference between Roth and the traditional IRAs.
你到底怎麼回事?這個是稅前
Fuck is wrong with you? The shit is pretax.
不,沒關係 很多人對此都感到很困惑
No, it's okay. A lot of people get confused by that.
不,這個傢伙想惹事 讓我們接受審計
This bitch is gonna mess around, get us audited.
- 說說你什麼意思 - 你有存了五年的發票嗎?
- Say what you mean. - You got five years' receipts, motherfucker?
脫衣舞俱樂部不是家庭辦公室!
And the strip club ain't no home office!
老黑,這是危險警告!
That's a red flag, nigga!
你這個大肉球!
You big beanbag-build bitch!
住手!你們都是朋友!對吧?
Stop it! You all friends! Right?
喬喬,你也許是對的
Now JoJo, you might be right.
脫衣舞俱樂部不是家庭辦公室
A strip club isn't a home office.
你在自找接受審計
You're asking to be audited, son.
但有理就比友誼還重要嗎?
But is being right more important than friendship? Huh?
吸取一下我的教訓吧
Take it from me.
我失去了我的黑朋友
I lost my black friend.
別失去你的
Don't lose yours.
抱一下
Hug.
抱一下,混蛋!
Hug, motherfuckers!
- 對不起 - 對不起
- I'm sorry. - I'm sorry, man.
- 我會永遠愛你 - 嘿,兄弟,這只是說說
- I'll love you forever. - Hey, bro, you know, it's just talk.
老兄,你準備好加入幫派了?
Say, cos, you ready to get put on the hood?
時刻準備著
I'm rolling.
蛋黃醬,我需要你好好想想
RUSSELL: Mayo, I need you to sink your mind into this, cos.
一旦你跨過這個門檻 混蛋們都會為你拼命
Once you step through this threshold, motherfuckers are ready to kill for you.
我是說整個兄弟會都會全力支持你
I mean a whole fraternity of motherfuckers gonna have your back.
但只有一條離開這個的路
But there's only one way out of this.
那就是當你的棺材入土時
That's when your casket drops into the ground.
所以從今往後...
So from this day forward...
你擁有永恆的保護...
you have eternal protection...
直到你往生
until your eternal demise.
我們這幫人做事都很嚴肅
We dead-ass serious about what we do.
如果你跨過這個門檻 然後回來...
And if you go through that threshold and you make it back...
我們會好好地善待你
we gonna be dead-ass serious about you.
是時候去虐待一些混蛋了
Time to smoke some fools.
一輩子都是克倫肖王的人
Crenshaw Kings for life, motherfucker.
差不多了
Hmm. Almost.
我們走吧
Let's roll.
嘿
SHONDA: Hey.
平安歸來
You come back safe.
珊達,我會的
I will, Shonda.
- 蛋黃醬,我們得走了 - 再見,寶貝
- MAN: We gotta go, Mayo. - Bye, baby.
我們走吧
RUSSELL: Let's roll, cos.
等一下!哦,該死!等等!
Hold up! Oh, shit! Wait, wait, wait!
哦,等等,等等!
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
嘿!我是達內爾!我是達內爾!
Hey! It's Darnell! It's Darnell!
- 我是達內爾! - 你在這裡幹嘛呢?
- It's Darnell! - What the fuck are you doing here?
可惡,表弟! 告訴他們把槍放下!
Shit, cousin! Man, tell them to put their guns down!
各位,放下槍吧
Man, put them up.
上帝!
DARNELL: God!
你怎麼回事? 你在做什麼?
What is your problem, man? What are you doing?
給我們一點時間
Man, give us a second.
我入會了 克倫肖王會從裡面保護我
I'm blooding in. Crenshaw Kings are gonna protect me on the inside.
詹姆斯,你要去殺個人? 你已經瘋了嗎?
So you're gonna go and kill somebody, James? Huh? Have you lost your fucking mind?
我必須這麼做,我別無選擇
I have to. I don't have a choice.
事實並非如此
That is not true.
詹姆斯,我來這裡要告訴你 我們可以證明你的清白
I came here to tell you we can clear your name, James.
但你得相信我
But you gotta trust me, man.
蛋黃醬,我們得走了
We gotta roll, Mayo.
“蛋黃醬”?
"Mayo"?
- 蛋黃醬是誰? - 我是蛋黃醬,這是我的幫名
- Who the fuck is Mayo? - I'm Mayo. It's my gang name.
它是“白色蛋黃醬”的縮寫 起因於我的膚色
It's short for "Mayonnaise" on account of my skin color.
我想出來的
I came up with that.
- 好的,那麼你要走了? - 什麼?
- Okay, you wanna go then? - What?
- 你想要走了? - 你在幹嘛呢?
- You wanna go? - What are you doing?
在你的槍上印滿指紋,這樣的話,如果你進監獄 我就會跟你一塊兒進
Putting fingerprints on your gun. If you go to jail, I'm going to jail with you.
那麼在你入獄並做出愚蠢決定之前 為什麼不考慮一下呢?
So before you out there and make a stupid-ass decision, why don't you think about that?
好了
There you go.
就這樣?我的指紋那麼容易去掉了?
That's it? My fingerprints are off that easy?
是的,差不多,完好如初 蛋黃醬,我們走吧
Pretty much. Good as new. Let's roll, Mayo.
詹姆斯,現在你有了選擇 有對的路,有錯的路
James, you got a choice right now. You got the right path, you got the wrong path.
詹姆斯,做出正確決定吧
Make the right decision, James.
聽從你的內心
Follow your heart, man.
在這事上你得相信我
James, you gotta trust me on this one.
哦,天哪!我差點就做了! 我差點去殺人!
Oh, my God! I almost did it! I almost killed a man!
我當時打算用這把槍
And I was gonna use this gun.
詹姆斯,把它收起來!住手!
James, put that away, man! Stop!
- 你怎麼回事? - 我不知道
- What is your problem? - I don't know.
他們在鼓動我...
They were just encouraging me...
他們在對我擊掌
and they were high-fiving me.
他們給了我這個大麻雪茄
They're passing me this sticky icky.
在妓女和皮條客之間...
And between the pot and the hos...
只是一種美味的原始感覺
it was just an ambrosia of primal sensations.
在一個短暫的瞬間 我知道了我的目的是什麼
And for one brief moment, I knew what my purpose was.
- 好的,好的 - 更不用提羅素了
- Okay, okay. - Not to mention Russell.
他有超凡魅力,真正天生的領導者 使我想起年輕時的羅納德·裡根
He's so charismatic. Real natural leader. Reminds me of a young Ronald Reagan.
嘿...
Hey...
謝謝你為我回來
Thank you for coming back for me.
謝謝你沒有做傻事,我們離開這裡
Thanks for not doing nothing stupid, man. Let's get out of here.
入獄前二十四小時
好的,聽聽這個
All right, so listen to this.
我查明馬丁車上的殘渣是鹹水
I figured out that the residue on Martin's car was saltwater.
然後我記起了英里數 原因在於我過去總是把里程表拍下來
Then I remembered the mileage. I used to take a picture of the odometer all the time...
- 以防人們投訴我駕車兜風 - 人們會那麼幹?太糟了
- to keep people from accusing me of joyriding. - People do that? That's awful.
是的,你就投訴了三次,你試圖讓我被解雇 但你以為我名叫安德烈
Yeah, you did it like three times. You tried to get me fired, but thought my name was Andre.
不管怎樣,看看這個: 馬丁過去每天都開一樣的七英里
Anyway, Martin used to drive the same exact seven miles every day.
但上周開始,他每天開五十六英里
But last week, he started driving 56 miles every day.
五十六英里!那麼我所做的是,我查了地圖
Fifty-six! So, what I did was, I checked the map.
結果發現這恰是到聖佩德羅 一個來回的距離
Turns out that's the exact distance of a round-trip to San Pedro.
鹹水,海洋,聖佩德羅
Saltwater, ocean, San Pedro.
我必須弄清楚他為什麼去聖佩德羅 這是我唯一不明白的事情
I just gotta figure out why he's going to San Pedro. That's the only thing I don't know.
他的遊艇
His yacht.
它被停在了港口
It's docked at the port.
- 他有遊艇? - 還有佛得角的一座島
- Fucker's got a yacht? - Mm-hm. And an island in Cape Verde...
- 那裡沒有引渡法 - 詹姆斯,那廝有一艘遊艇和一座島?
- where there are no extradition laws. - Fucker's got a yacht and a island, James?
混蛋在詹姆斯·邦德電影中 為大反派效命!
Fucking working for a villain in a James Bond movie!
他就要逃跑了
He's gonna make a run for it.
除非蛋黃醬能阻止他
Not if Mayo can stop him.
蛋黃醬和巧克力
Mayo and Chocolat.
- “巧克力”? - 巧克力
- "Chocolat"? - Chocolat.
- 那是我的小名嗎? - 那就是你的小名
- Is that supposed to be my nickname? - That's your nickname.
我會想個更好的 車程還有一段時間呢
I'll do better. We have the whole car ride.
蛋黃醬和咖啡
Mayo and Coffee.
蛋黃醬和軟糖
Mayo and Fudge.
- 我不想要這樣的名字,就叫我達內爾 - 來吧,軟糖!
- DARNELL: I don't want one. Just call me Darnell. - JAMES: Hit it, Fudge!
入獄前二十三時 十四分四十九秒
就在那裡,他的船 海上通知
There it is. There's his boat. The Sea Note.
海上通知?什麼玩意兒
The Sea Note? What a dick.
快點
Come on.
詹姆斯,蹲下 你得蹲下
DARNELL: Get down, James. You gotta get down.
- 那些都是守衛? - 我想是的
- Are those guards? - I think so.
- 很多守衛 - 是的
- DARNELL: There's a lot of them. - JAMES: Yeah.
那台電腦
There's the computer.
我看到了
I see it.
詹姆斯,你得低下身子!
James, you gotta get low!
賈盧伊特馬紹爾群島
ENGINE REVS
- 哦,不,他們準備離開了 - 該死,我們得跳上船
- JAMES: Oh, no. They're getting ready to leave. - Shit. We gotta jump.
好的
All right.
- 撒開我的手! - 抱歉,我很緊張
- Get off my hand! - Sorry, I'm nervous.
我們走吧!
Let's go!
達內爾!我做到了!
Darnell! I made it!
鬆開我的臉!
JAMES: Let go of my face!
詹姆斯,你堅持住了!
- That's all you, James. All you, James! - Aah!
好,快,這邊
Okay. Come on, this way.
就是這個
There it is.
- 快點,動作快 - 哦,可惡!
Come on. Let's go. Let's go. Oh, shit!
鬆開!鬆開!
Get off! Get off!
鬆開
Get off.
該死
Dammit.
夥計們,你們活到頭了
This is the end, guys.
你完蛋了
You going down.
太棒了 我的一生都是在克倫肖度過...
That's great. I spend my whole life in Crenshaw...
而現在我就要被某個 來自比佛利山莊的白人殺掉了?
and now I'm about to get killed by some white guy from Beverly Hills?
- 在一艘遊艇上! - 我很抱歉
- On a yacht! - I'm so sorry.
詹姆斯,把電腦交出來
Hand over the computer, James.
拜託,你就是想不通嗎?
Come on. Just can't get it through your head?
像你這樣的人永遠只會當替罪羊 因為你們很弱
Guys like you will always be the fall guy because you're weak.
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
詹姆斯?詹姆斯,不,詹姆斯,不要
James? James. No. James, please.
該死,詹姆斯 不要,不要,詹姆斯
Goddamn, James. Please, please, James.
我我判處你到在安全級別 最高的監獄服刑十年
I sentence you to 10 years in a maximum security prison.
你會得到這個:
You about to get this:
哦,他們在聖昆丁廷亂搞
Oh, they be fucking in San Quentin.
- 在這棟房子裡? - 嘴巴被塞滿了蛋蛋
- In this house? - Mouth full of balls.
- 蛋黃醬,回來 - 全盤接受吧
- Come back, Mayo. - Take it all.
當人生塞給你一根大屌時 夠你用十年的了
When life puts a dick in your mouth, you make dickade.
去給人吹簫吧
Go suck a dick.
你的卡波耶拉很強!
Your Capoeira's strong!
現在你必須把你的能量帶給世界
Now you must bring your power into the world.
什麼?詹姆斯,你在幹嘛呢?
What? James. What are you doing?
我已經被擺布很久了
I've been pushed around for too long.
現在時機到了,我能感覺到
Now it is time. I can feel it.
- 詹姆斯,是時候幹嘛? - 保護那台電腦!
- Time for what, James? - Protect the computer!
該死!我不想要那台電腦!
Shit! I don't want the computer!
祝福踢!
Bên??o kick!
哦,天啊!
Oh, God!
哦,可惡!
Oh, shit!
放開我!住手!不!
Leave me alone! Stop! No!
詹姆斯!詹姆斯!
James! James!
沒事的!下去,快點!
All right, get down there. Come on.
太空搖擺!斧子腳!
SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
蛋黃醬和巧克力,混蛋!
Mayo and Chocolat, motherfuckers!
詹姆斯,你還真是深藏不漏啊
Aah! James, you mean to tell me you could do this shit the whole time?
卡波耶拉不能被使用 除非卡波耶拉被要求使用
Capoeira must never be used unless Capoeira is required.
我們走吧
Let's go.
混蛋!
Motherfuckers!
好吧!好吧!
Okay! Okay!
旋風腿!
JAMES SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
過來!
IN ENGLISH Come here!
我們只會打贏架!
That's what we do!
混...!放手!
Mother...! Get off!
詹姆斯
James.
做我們在操場常做的那個
Do like we used to do in the yard.
好的!詹姆斯,沒問題
Yeah! You got it, James.
詹姆斯,太棒了,詹姆斯,擊中他
Fuck yeah, James. Get his ass, James.
天啊
God.
我拿到電腦了
DARNELL: I got the computer.
- 救生船,快點 - 好的
- Lifeboat. Come on. - All right.
嘿,那個卡波耶拉太厲害了
Hey, that Capoeira shit was amazing.
但你也從我這兒學到了些東西 詹姆斯,對吧?
But you learned some of that shit from me too. Right, James?
這裡發生什麼事了? 你對我的船到底做了什麼?
James. What's going on here? What the hell did you do to my boat?
去他的這條船!
Man, fuck this boat!
我們拿著你陷害你女婿的證據 你這個狗娘養的
We taking the evidence that you framed your son-in-law with, sick son of a bitch.
馬丁,你怎麼能這樣對我? 十年牢獄?!
How could you do this to me, Martin? Ten years in prison?
詹姆斯,你知道我不是有意害你
James, you realize that I didn't mean to hurt you.
我很喜歡你,但喜馬拉雅老虎輸了
I'm very fond of you, but Himalayan Tiger tanked...
我得從其他地方弄錢 我沒有選擇,不是你就是我
and I had to get the money from somewhere. I had no choice. It was you or me.
這聽起來像是個選擇!
That sounds like a choice!
詹姆斯,去他的,我們走
James, fuck him. We're leaving.
下次你想要存儲什麼假賬 記得找一台iPad
And next time you wanna store some fraud shit, get an iPad.
快點,詹姆斯
Come on, James.
- 哦,見鬼 - 艾麗莎
- Oh, my damn. - Alissa.
- 詹姆斯,爸爸,他在這裡幹嘛呢? - 沒事的,親愛的
- James. Daddy, what's he doing here? - MARTIN: It's fine, honey.
詹姆斯
Uh, James.
我有個很棒的想法 你為什麼不跟我們來呢?
I have a wonderful idea. Why don't you come with us?
我們在佛得角開始了全新的生活 沒人要進監獄
We'll start a whole new life in Cape Verde and nobody has to go to prison.
難道你不想要...
Don't you want...
一座大大的島?
a big, big island?
- 你參與這事了? - 沒有,最初沒有
- Were you in on this? - No, not at first.
而當他告訴我這事時 我真的很生他的氣
And when he told me about it, I was really mad at him.
但後來他解釋 他如何能夠隱藏大部分錢...
But then he explained how he was able to hide most of the money...
所以真的無害
so, really, there's no harm done.
詹姆斯,現在還有時間 獲得你想要的一切
James, now there's still time to get everything you want.
一切
Everything.
不!我什麼都不想要
No! I don't want any of it.
你是個白妞兒
- And you got a white girl's ass. - Ah!
乾得好,嘿,詹姆斯 你想要關掉嗎?我上面什麼都沒留下
Thattaboy. Hey, James, do you wanna switch off, man? I got nothing left up top.
- 快,把它扔進救生艇 - 沒錯,然後我們可以離開這裡
- JAMES: Quick, throw it in the Zodiac. - Right. Then we can get the fuck out of here.
可惡!該死!
- Shit! Goddamn it! - Aah!
我真誠地抱歉 事情必須這樣了結
I am genuinely sorry it had to end this way.
在我們出了防波堤後,就殺了他們
When we clear the breakwater, shoot them.
你不必這樣做
You ain't got to do this, man.
You ain't got to do this.
爸爸,似乎你想到了一切,不是嗎?
Well, Dad, looks like you thought of everything, didn't you?
你總是先我一步
You were always one step ahead of me.
除了你忘了一個小細節
Except you forgot one little detail.
哪來的?
Where'd that come from?
監獄搜身第一規則:
First rule in prison pat-downs:
永遠都要檢查肛門
Always check the anus.
有人學會了怎麼把東西藏到屁股裡
Someone learned how to keister.
沒錯,笨蛋們
- Ew. - That's right. Nuts and butts.
你指我?好的 你要這樣做嗎?
You point? Okay. That's how you wanna do it?
你指他,我指馬丁
You point at him. I'll point at Martin.
不管怎樣,如果我死了,馬丁會死
Either way. So if I die, Martin's going.
所以你搞定,殺我,馬丁會中槍
So you figure it out. Shoot me, Martin gets shot.
蓋爾,現在該你採取行動了
Ball's in your court, Gayle.
- 艾麗莎? - 殺了她
- Alissa? - Shoot her.
殺了她,總之你要殺了那個賤人
Shoot her. You need to shoot that bitch anyway.
你不會殺我的
You're not gonna shoot me.
你在浪費時間,警察會隨時趕到
You're wasting time. Police'll be here any second.
沒錯,我們說的是真警察
That's right. We're talking the real police.
警察會開著裝有警報器的船到這兒...
The ones that's gonna come here on boats with sirens on them...
會帶著會水的警犬 讓我跟你說說會水的警犬
that's got dogs that can swim. Let me tell you something about swimming dogs.
我來告訴你吧,你會滿嘴跑火車
Now, let me tell you, you're gonna bullshit a bullshitter...
把謊話吹得似是而非
just make the bullshit plausible.
這是美國聯邦法院執行官 準備登船
MAN: This is the U. S. Marshall Service. Prepare to be boarded.
你要載著逃犯
You are carrying a fugitive.
太棒了!
Yes!
沒錯
Heh. Hell yeah.
哦,可惡
Oh, shit.
怎麼會?
How?
記得你那個蹩腳律師 給我的這個腳鐐嗎?
Remember this bracelet that crooked lawyer of yours gave me?
根據我的計算 我們應該正在郡界之外
By my calculation we should be well outside the county line.
監獄學校開學了
Prison school's in session, bitch.
而有人剛剛畢業了
And somebody just graduated.
太好了,太好了
That's perfect. That's perfect.
很棒,是嗎?
That's great, right?
注意,海上通知 我們是美國聯邦法院執行官
Attention Sea Note. This is the U.S. Marshal Service.
- 馬丁,你要去哪兒? - 是啊,你要去哪兒?
- DARNELL: Where you going? Huh, Martin? - JAMES: Where you going?
什麼?!
What?!
- 看看你! - 我知道
- Look at you, man! - I know.
天哪,看看你!
God, look at you!
你把它放到...?在你的屁股裡 放在你屁股裡
Where did you put...? That was in your ass. That was in your ass.
電腦證明我無罪
JAMES: The computer proved I was innocent.
馬丁因詐騙被捕 篡改證據和妨礙司法公正
Martin was arrested for fraud, tampering with evidence and obstruction of justice.
我會聯繫我的律師 爸爸?
ALISSA: And I will be contacting my attorney. Daddy?
至於我 我洗脫了所有與挪用公款有關的指控
JAMES: As for me, I was cleared of all charges related to the embezzlement.
看來我們搞定了
So I guess we did it.
蛋黃醬和巧克力
Mayo and Chocolate.
感謝上帝 我們不會再需要這個了
- Heh. - Thank God we won't be needing this anymore.
這把非法的未經許可的槍
This illegal, unlicensed gun.
- 詹姆斯 你應該把這東西丟掉 - 槍!
- Okay, you should really get rid of that thing. - MAN: Gun!
- 丟了它! - 哦,該死
- MAN: Drop it! - Oh, shit.
我最後因持有未經許可的武器 被拘留六個月
JAMES: I did end up getting six months for carrying an unlicensed weapon.
但多謝達內爾,我準備好了
But, thanks to Darnell, I was ready.
監獄就像最純粹的生活
Prison is like life distilled to its purest form.
你尊重別人,別人就尊重你
Give respect to get respect.
但是,如果你讓別人亂吃你的食物 那你就是娘炮
But most of all, if you let someone fuck with your food, you're a punk fuck bitch.
有人應該告訴你 這個蛋黃醬過期了
Someone should have told you this Mayo went bad.
老子揍死你
I'm gonna punch you in the fuck!
老子弄死你
I'm gonna shit you!
聖操蛋快樂,混蛋!
Merry Dickmas, Santa Cock!
馬丁準備得就不怎麼樣了 但他也汲取了寶貴的教訓
Martin didn't do as well. But he learned a valuable lesson too.
他們在聖昆丁廷被搞乾翻了
They be fucking in San Quentin.
- 你好嗎? - 搞乾得天翻地覆
- How ya doing? - JAMES: A whole lot of fucking.
嘿!打開,打開
Hey! Open up. Open up.
珊達每天來看我
JAMES: Shonda visited me every day.
我從未認為監獄會是 我學著再次愛別人的地方
I never thought prison would be the place I learned to love again...
但這就是所發生的事
but that's what happened.
不,不,不!她還沒完成,她還沒完成呢
No, no, no! She's not done. She hasn't finished yet.
不,這不是你想的那樣,我們戀愛了
No, it's not what you think. We're in love.
我幫助聯邦調查局找到 並歸還馬丁偷走的所有資產
JAMES: I helped the FBI find and return all the assets Martin stole.
作為回報,他們解凍了我的銀行賬戶 我知道把我的錢投到哪裡
In return, they unfroze my bank accounts, and I knew just where to invest my money.
盛大開業
不錯吧?
DARNELL: It's good?
很棒,是吧?
It's good, right?
瑪凱拉,你為爸爸感到驕傲嗎?
Makayla, you proud of Daddy?
爸爸做得很棒吧?抱我一下
Daddy did good? Give me a hug.
爸爸,我喜歡你的洗車中心
Daddy, I like your car wash.
寶貝,你喜歡我很高興
I'm glad you like it, sweetie.
看來你倖存下來了
I see you survived.
蛋黃醬,我猜你變堅強了
I guess you got hard, Mayo.
不,是你讓我堅強的
No. You made me hard.
過來
Come here, man. Heh.
你讓我堅挺了
You made me hard.
那麼堅挺
So hard.
你使我如此堅挺
You got me so hard.
兄弟,我也很高興見到你 我很高興見到你
I'm happy to see you too, big fella. I'm happy to see you.
有段時間我不能堅挺...
There was a moment where I stopped being hard...
但我想到了你 這使我再次堅挺
but I thought of you, and it got me hard again.
我太感謝你了
And I can't ever thank you.
好了
All right.
歡迎回家 快,我們上車
Welcome home, man. Come on, let's get in the car.
詹姆斯,你看起來氣色不錯
You look good, James.
詹姆斯,歡迎回到自由世界 你想怎麼慶祝?
Welcome back to the free world, James. How you wanna celebrate?
你知道我想要什麼嗎? 一份《華爾街日報》還有一個四十
JAMES: You know what I'd like to get my hands on? A Wall Street Journal and a 40.
那會是一個完美的周日早晨
Now that'd be a perfect Sunday morning.